the following is a conversation with
以下是与之对话
Jeff Atwood he is the co-founder of
杰夫阿特伍德他的联合创始人
Stack Overflow
堆栈溢出
Stack Exchange websites that are visited
堆栈访问的Exchange网站
by millions of people every single day
数以百万计 的人 每一天
much like with Wikipedia it is difficult
很像维基百科很难
to understate the impact on global
低估 了对全球的影响
knowledge and productivity that these
知识和生产力这些
networks of sites have created Jeff is
网站的网站创造了杰夫
also the author of the famed blog coding
也是着名的博客编码的作者
horror and the founder of discourse an
恐怖和话语的创始人
open-source software project that seeks
寻求的开源软件项目
to improve the quality of our online
提高我们的 在线 质量
community discussions this conversation
社区讨论这个对话
is part of the MIT course on artificial
是 麻省理工学院人工课程的 一部分
general intelligence and the artificial
一般情报和人工
intelligence podcast if you enjoy it
智能播客， 如果你喜欢它
subscribe on youtube itunes or your
订阅youtube itunes或您的
podcast provider of choice or simply
播客提供商的选择或简单
connect with me on twitter at Lex
在 Lex的 Twitter上与我联系
Friedman spelled Fri D and now here's my
弗里德曼拼写了Fri D，现在这里是我的
conversation with Jeff Atwood having
与杰夫阿特伍德的谈话
co-created and managed for a few years
共同创建和管理了几年
the world's largest community of
世界上最大的社区
programmers in Stack Overflow ten years
Stack Overflow程序员十年
ago what do you think motivates most
你以前认为最有动力的是什么？
programmers is it fame fortune glory
程序员是名利双收的荣耀
process of programming itself or is it
编程本身的过程或是它
the sense of belonging to a community
属于 社会意识
it's puzzles really I think it's this
它 真的很难，我认为就是这样
idea of working on puzzles independently
独立工作的想法
of other people and just solving a
其他人，只是解决一个
problem sort of like on your own almost
问题有点 像你 自己差不多
although you know nobody really works
虽然你知道没人 真的有用
alone and programming anymore but I will
单独和编程了，但我会
say there's that there's an aspect of
说有一个方面
sort of hiding yourself away and just
有点隐藏自己和 公正
sort of beating on a problem until you
有点打击问题， 直到你
solve it like brute force basically to
解决它就像蛮力基本上一样
me it's what a lot of programming is is
我是很多 编程的
like the computer so fast right you can
就像电脑那么快你就可以
do things that would take forever for a
做一些永远需要 的事情
human but you just do them like so many
人类， 但 你 就像这么多人一样
times and so often that you get the
时间 经常让你得到
answer right you're saying just the pure
回答对你说的只是纯粹的
act of tinkering with the code yes is is
修补代码的行为是的
the thing that drives most probably the
驱动最有可能 的 事
joy the struggle balance within the joy
欢乐的喜悦之内的斗争平衡
of overcoming the the brute-force
克服蛮力
process of pain and suffering that
痛苦和痛苦的过程
eventually leads to something that
最终导致一些
actually works well data is fun too like
实际工作 以及数据是好玩 太像
there's this thing called the the
有这个叫做的东西
shuffling problem like the naive shuffle
洗牌问题就像天真的洗牌一样
that most programmers right has a huge
大多数程序员都拥有巨大的权利
flaw and there's a lot of articles
缺陷， 有很多 文章
online about this because it can be
在线关于此，因为它可以
really bad if you're like a casino and
如果你像赌场一样 真的很 糟糕
you have an unsophisticated programmer
你有一个不成熟的 程序员
writing your shuffle algorithm there's
写你的shuffle 算法
surprising ways to get this wrong but
奇怪的方法来解决这个问题但是
the neat thing is the way to figure that
整洁的东西是 想出这个的方法
out is just to run your shuffle a bunch
out只是为了你的 洗牌一堆
of times and see like how many
时间和看多少
orientations of cards you get you should
你得到 的 卡的 方向 应该
get an equal distribution of all the
得到所有的平等分配
cards and with the naive method of
卡和天真的方法
shuffling if you just look at the data
如果你只看数据就洗牌
if you just brute force and say okay I
如果你只是蛮力并说好的我
don't know what's gonna happen
不知道会 发生 什么
you just write a program that does it a
你只需编写一个程序就可以了
billion times and then see what the
十亿次， 然后看看是什么
buckets look like of the data and the
桶看起来像数据和
Monty Hall problem is another example of
蒙蒂霍尔问题 是另一个例子
that where you have three doors and
但如你有三个门 ，
somebody gives you information about
有人给你的信息
another door so the correct answer is
另一扇门，所以 正确 答案是
you should always switch and the Monty
你应该 总是切换 和蒙蒂
Hall problem which is not intuitive and
霍尔问题不直观
people it freaks people out all the time
人们总是把人吓坏了
right but you can solve it with data if
没关系，你可以与 如果 数据解决这个问题
you write a program that does the Monty
你写了一个程序， 它的蒙蒂
Hall you know game and then never
霍尔， 你知道游戏，然后永远不会
switches and always switches just
开关和始终 只是 切换
compare you would immediately see that
比较你会立即看到
you don't have to be smart right you
你不必聪明 对你
know to figure out the answer
知道找出答案
algorithmically you can just brute force
在算法上你可以蛮力
it out with data and say well I know the
用数据说出来并说得好我知道
answer is this because I ran the program
回答 是因为我运行了 程序
a billion times and these are the data
十亿次，这些都是数据
buckets that I got from it right so
水桶， 我从中得到了 这样的权利
empirically find it but what's the joy
凭经验找到它，但是快乐是什么
of that what so for you for you
那 对你 来说 如此
personally outside of family what
亲自外面的家庭什么
motivates you in this process
在这个过程中激励你
yes well to be honest I don't really
是的，说实话， 我 不是 真的
write a lot of code anymore like what I
写了很多代码就像我一样
do at discourse is like manager II stuff
在话语中做的就像经理二的东西
which I always kind of despised right
我总是那种鄙视的权利
like as a programmer you think of
就像你想到的程序员一样
managers as people who don't really do
经理人并不是真正做到的人
anything themselves but the weird thing
什么都不是，但 奇怪的 是
about code is like you realize that like
关于代码就像你意识到的那样
language is code like the ability to
语言的能力等代码
direct other people lets you get more
直接其他人可以让你获得更多
stuff than you've done then you could by
比 你已经完成的 东西， 你可以通过
yourself anyway you should write
无论如何你应该写自己
languages code languages community
语言代码语言社区
communication yeah those are humans yes
沟通是的那些是人类是的
you can think of it as a systemic so
你可以把它想象成一个系统性的
what what is it like to be what makes
什么是什么样子是 什么让
before we get into program it what makes
在我们进入程序之前， 它是什么造成的
a good manager what makes a good leader
一个好的经理是什么让一个好的领导者
well I think a leader it's all about
我认为 这是 一个 领导者
leading by example first of all like
以身作则 都喜欢 的第一个
sort of doing and being the things that
做某事和做事
you want to be now this can be kind of
你想成为现在这个可种
exhausting particular you have kids
特别是你有孩子
because you realize that your kids are
因为你意识到你的孩子是
watching you like all the time like even
看着 你一样都 喜欢连 时间
in ways that you've stopped seeing
以你不再看到的方式
yourself like the hardest person to see
你自己就像最难看的人
on the planet is really yourself right
在这个星球上真的是你自己
it's funnier to see other people and and
看到其他人和他人更有趣
and make judgments about them but
并且对他们 进行审判 ，但
yourself like your
你自己喜欢你的
for biased you don't actually see
对于有偏见的你实际上并没有看到
yourself the way other people see you
你自己就像别人看到你一样
often you're very very hard on yourself
你经常对自己 非常 努力
in a way that other people really aren't
以某种方式， 其他人 真的不是
going to be so you know that's one of
将会如此，你知道这是其中 之一
the insights is you know you've got to
这些见解是你知道的
be really diligent about thinking like
非常 勤奋的想法
am i behaving in a way that represents
我是在行为代表的方式
how I want other people to behave right
我多么希望其他人的行为 的权利
like leading through example there's a
像通过例子那样有一个
lot of examples of leaders that really
真的 很多领导人的例子
mess this up right like they make
像他们做的那样把它搞得一团糟
decisions that are like wow that's why
这些决定就像哇哇那样的原因
would you know it's just it's it's it's
你知道吗，就是它就是它
a bad example for other people so I
对于其他人来说这是一个坏榜样所以我
think leading by example is one the
以身作则，以身作则
other one I believe it is working really
另一个我相信它真的有效
hard now I don't mean like working
现在我很努力， 我不是说工作
exhaustively but like showing a real
详尽但却表现出真实
passion for the problem like you know
对你所知道的问题的热情
not necessarily your solution the
不一定是你的解决方案
problem but the problem itself is just
问题但问题本身就是
one that you really believe in like with
一个你真正 相信的人
discourse for example the problem that
话语，例如，问题
we're looking at which is my current
我们正在 研究哪些是 我目前的
project is how do you get people in
项目是如何让人们进入的
groups to communicate in a way that
团体以 某种方式 进行 沟通
doesn't like break down into the howling
不喜欢分解 成嚎叫
of wolves right like how do you deal
对狼来说就像你怎么处理
with trolling not like technical
拖钓不像技术
problems of how do I get people to post
如何让人们 发帖的问题
paragraphs how do I get people to use
段落如何让人们使用
bold how to get people to use complete
大胆如何让人们使用完整
sentences although those are problems as
句子虽然这些都是问题
well but like how do I get people to get
好吧， 但我喜欢如何让人们得到
along with each other
随着彼此
right like and then solve whatever
对，然后解决任何问题
problem it is they set up to solver you
问题是他们设置解决你
know reach some consensus on discussion
知道在讨论上达成一些共识
or just like not hurt each other even
或者仅仅是想不伤害对方，甚至
right like maybe it's a discussion
好吧，也许这是一个讨论
doesn't really matter but are people
真的不重要，但是人
like yelling at each other right and why
喜欢互相吼叫， 为什么
right like that's not the purpose of
这样的权利不是为了
this kind of communication so I would
这样的沟通，所以我会
say you know leadership is about you
说你知道领导是 关于你的
know setting an example you know doing
知道你 的设置 知道 这样 一个 例子
the things that represent what you want
那些 代表 你想要的东西
to be and making sure that you're
是的， 并确保你
actually doing those things and there's
实际上做那些事情就是这样
a trick to that too because the things
这 也是一个伎俩， 因为事情
you don't do also say a lot about what
你不这样做也说了很多 关于什么
you are yeah so let's pause on that one
你是的，所以让我们暂停一下
so those two things are fascinating so
所以这两件事情都很吸引人
how do you have as a leader as that
你怎么有作为一个领导者为
self-awareness so you just said it's
自我意识， 所以你只是说它
really hard to be self-aware so for you
真的 很难 自我意识所以对你来说
personally or maybe for other leaders
个人或可能为其他领导人
you've seen or look up to how do you
你见过或看过你怎么样
know the both that the things you're
知道你所做的事情
doing are the wrong things to be doing
这样做是错误的东西是 做
the way you speak to others the way you
你的方式别人说话 你 的方式
behave and the things you're not doing
表现和你不做的事情
how do you how do you get that service
你怎么得到这项 服务
there's two aspects that one is like
一个是 两个方面
processing feedback that you're getting
处理你得到的反馈
so how you get feedback well right sorry
所以你如何得到很好的反馈 对不起
are you getting feedback right like so
你是否 正确 得到 反馈？
one way we do it for example a discourse
我们这样做的一种方式，例如 话语
we have three co-founders and we
我们有三位联合创始人和我们
periodically talk about decisions before
之前定期谈论决定
we make them so it's not like one person
我们制造它们所以它不像一个人
can make a mistake or like
会犯错误或喜欢
that's you know there can be
那你知道可以吗？
misunderstanding things like this so
误解这样的事情如此
it's part of like group consensus of
这是小组共识的一部分
leadership is like it's good to have I
领导就像拥有我一样好
think
认为
systems where there's one leader and
系统中有一个领导者和
that leader has the rule of absolute law
那个领导者有绝对法则
are just really dangerous and my
我真的很危险
experience for communities for example
例如 ， 社区的经验
like a few of communities run by one
像一些由一个人经营的社区
person that one person makes all the
人 ，一个 人做所有的
decisions that person's gonna have a bad
决定那个人 会有坏事
day something could happen to that
一天事情会发生在 那
person you know something you know
你 认识的 人
there's a lot of variables so like at
有很多的变量 ，这样在像
first when you think about leadership
第一，当你想到 领导
haven't have multiple people doing
没有多个人在做
leadership and have them talk amongst
领导并让他们互相交谈
each other so giving each other feedback
彼此互相给予反馈
about the decisions that they're making
关于他们正在 做出 的决定
and then when you do get feedback I
然后当你得到反馈 我
think there's that little voice in your
我觉得 你的声音 很小
head right like or your gut or wherever
像是在你的直觉 或任何地方
you want to put it in your putti I think
你想把它放在你的putti 我想
that voice is really important like I
那个声音和我一样重要
think most people who have any kind of
想想大多数人都有
moral compass or like want to do most
道德指南针或喜欢想做的最多
people want to do the right thing I do
人们想做 我做的正确的事
believe that I mean there might be a
相信 我的意思是有可能是一个
handful of sociopaths out there that
那里有少数反社会人士
don't but most people they want other
不要，但大多数人都想要其他人
people to think of them as a good person
人们 认为他们是一个很好的人
and why wouldn't you right like do you
为什么你不喜欢你
want people to despise you I mean that's
希望人们 鄙视你我的意思是那个
just weird right so you have that little
只是很奇怪，所以你有 那么一 点点
voice that sort of the angel and devil
语音那种天使和魔鬼
on your shoulder sort of talking to you
在你肩膀上跟你说话
about like what you're doing how you're
大约像你在做什么 ，你是怎么
doing how does it make you feel to make
做它是如何让你 感觉到的
these decisions right and I think having
这些决定是正确的，我认为
some attunement to that voice is
对这种声音的一些调整是
important but you said that voice also
重要， 但你也说 了声音
for I think this is a programmer
因为我认为这是程序员
situation to what sometimes the devil on
情况 有时 什么 魔鬼上
the shoulder is a little a little too
肩膀也有点儿
loud so you a little too self-critical
大声， 所以你有点过于自我批评
for a lot of developers and especially
对很多 开发商 ， 尤其是
when you have introverted personality
当你性格内向时
how do you struggle with the
你是如何 与挣扎的？
self-criticism other criticism others so
自我批评其他批评 别人 如此
one of the things of leadership is to do
领导的一件事 就是 去做
something that's not potentially
一些不可能的东西
unpopular or what people doubt you and
不受欢迎或人们怀疑你 和
you still go through with the decision
你仍然会 做出决定
so what's that balance like I think you
那就是我认为 你的 平衡
have to walk people through your
必须让人们通过你的
decision-making right like if if this is
决策 权如果是这样的话
where blogging is really important
博客非常重要
communication is so important again code
沟通是如此重要的代码
language is just another kind of code is
语言只是另一种代码
like here is the program by which I
像这里是我的程序
arrived at the conclusion that I'm gonna
到了我要去的结论
reach right it's one thing to say like
到达右 它是一回事 ，说喜欢
this is decisions final
这是最终的决定
deal with it right that's not usually
正确处理它并不常见
satisfying people but if you say look
满足的人，但如果你说看
you know we've been thinking this
你知道我们一直在想 这个
problem for a while here's some stuff
问题有一段时间了
that's happened here's what we think is
这里发生的事情是什么，我们认为是
right here's our goals here's one
就在这里我们的 目标是 一个
achieve and we've looked at these
实现，我们看了 这些
options and we think this of available
选项， 我们认为这 是可用的
options is the best option people be
选项是 人们 的 最佳选择
like oh okay
喜欢 哦没关系
alright maybe I don't totally agree with
好吧也许我不完全 同意
you but I can kind of see where you're
你但我可以看到你在哪里
coming from and like
来自 和喜欢
see it's not just arbitrary decision
看到它不仅仅是武断的决定
delivered from a cloud of flames in the
从 火焰中 的云 交付
sky right it's like a human trying to
天空 正好就像人类想要的那样
reach some kind of consensus about you
达成某种关于 你 的共识
know goals and their goals might be
知道目标和他们的目标可能是
different than yours that's completely
完全不同于你的
legit right but if you're making that
合法的权利，但如果你这样做
clear it's like oh well the reason we
清楚它就像我们的原因哦
don't agree is because we have totally
不同意是 因为我们完全
different goals right like how could we
不同的目标就像我们怎么样
agree it's not that you're a bad person
同意这并不是说你是一个坏人
it's that we have radically different
这是我们完全不同的
goals in mind when we started looking
我们开始寻找时的目标
this problem and the other one you said
这个问题和你说的另一个问题
is passion so or hard work sorry well
激情所以还是努力工作 好 难过
those are tied together to me out in my
那些被捆绑在一起的我
mind say Hardware compassionate like for
心灵说 硬件 富有同情心
me like I just really love the problem
我喜欢我 真的很 喜欢这个问题
discourse is sending out to solve
话语正在发出 来解决
because in a way it's like there's a
因为在某种程度上它就像是一个
there's a vision of the world where it
那里是世界的愿景在那里
all devolves into Facebook basically
所有人都基本上都进入了Facebook
owning everything and every aspect of
拥有一切和每个 方面
human communication right and this has
人类的沟通权利，这有
always been kind of a scary world for me
对我来说一直都是一个 可怕的世界
um first cuz I don't I think Facebook is
嗯，第一个因为我 不认为Facebook 是
really good at execution I gotta
真的很擅长执行我必须
compliment them they're very competent
恭维他们，他们非常称职
in terms of what they're doing but
就他们正在做什么而言
Facebook has not much of a moral compass
Facebook没有多少道德 指南针
in terms of Facebook cares about
在 Facebook关心 方面
Facebook really they don't really care
Facebook 真的他们并不在乎
about you and your problems what they
关于你和你的问题他们是什么
care about is how big they can make
关心的是他们能做多大
Facebook right is that you're talking
Facebook 正确的是你在说话
about the company or just a mechanism
关于公司 或只是一个机制
how Facebook works kind of both really
Facebook如何真正起作用
right like and the idea with discourse
对话和话语的想法
the reason I'm so passionate about it is
我 对它 充满热情的原因 是
because I believe every community should
因为我相信每个社区 都应该
have the right to own themselves right
有权拥有 自己的权利
like they should have their own software
他们应该拥有自己的 软件
that they can run that belongs to them
他们可以运行属于他们的
that's their space where they can set
这是他们 可以设置 的空间
the rules and if they don't like it they
规则，如果他们不喜欢 它们
can move to different hosting or you
可以移动到 不同的主机或你
know whatever they need they need to
知道他们需要什么， 他们 需要
have it can happen but like this this
它会发生， 但像这样
idea of a company town we're all human
公司城镇的 想法 我们 都是人
communication is implicitly owned by
沟通是由...隐含拥有的
whatsapp Instagram and Facebook and its
whatsapp Instagram和Facebook 及其
really disturbing too because Facebook
真的令人不安， 因为Facebook
is really smart like I said they're
真的很聪明， 就像我说的那样
great at execution buying and what's
擅长执行购买和什么
happened buying Instagram were
发生了买Instagram的事
incredibly smart decisions and they also
非常聪明的决定，他们也
do this thing on if you know but they
如果你知道，那就做这件事
have this VPN software that they give
他们提供这个VPN软件
away for free on smartphones and it
在智能手机上免费使用它
indirectly feeds all the the data about
间接地提供有关的所有数据
the traffic back to Facebook so they can
流量回到 Facebook所以他们可以
see what's actually getting popular
看看实际上 流行的是什么
through the VPNs right they have low
通过VPN权利他们有低
level access to the network data because
水平对 网络 的访问数据，因为
users have let them have that so ok
用户已经让他们那么好了
let's let's take a small pause here
让我们，让我们 一个小小的 停顿在这里
first of all discourse can you talk
首先 论述你可以谈的
about can you lay out the land of all
关于你可以布置所有的土地吗？
the different ways you can have
你 可以 有不同的方式
community so there's Stack Overflow that
社区所以有Stack Overflow
you've built
你已经建成了
there's discourse yeah so Stack Overflow
有话语是的，所以Stack Overflow
is kind of like a wiki Wikipedia you
有点像维基百科维基百科
talk
谈论
and it's a very specific scalpel very
这是一个非常具体的手术刀
focused so what is the purpose of
所以重点是什么目的
discourse and maybe contrast that with
话语 ，也许与之对比
Facebook first of all say what is this
Facebook 首先 要说的是这是什么
course yeah start from the beginning
当然是 从 一开始就开始
well let me start with the very being so
那么，让我开始很 是如此
Stack Overflow is very structured wiki
Stack Overflow是非常结构化的wiki
style QA for programmers right and that
程序员权利和风格QA
was the problem we first worked on it
是我们第一次研究它的问题
when we started we thought it was
当我们开始时，我们认为 它是
discussions because we looked at like
讨论， 因为我们看起来像
programming forums and other things but
编程论坛和其他东西， 但
we quickly realized we were doing QA
我们很快意识到我们正在做QA
which is a very narrow subset of human
这是一个非常狭窄的人类子集
communication sizes so when you start
通信 大小，所以当你开始
Stack Overflow you thought you didn't
Stack Overflow你以为你没有
even know the QA you know it would be
甚至知道你知道 这将 是 QA
well we didn't know we did we had an
好吧，我们不知道我们做了什么
idea of like ok these are things that we
像 确定 的思路 ，这些都是我们
see working online we had a goal right
看到在线工作， 我们有一个目标
our goal was there was this site experts
我们的目标是有这个网站的专家
exchange with a very unfortunate thank
交流时非常不幸的谢谢
you for killing that site yeah I know
你杀了那个网站我知道
right like a lot of people don't
像很多人一样没有
remember it anymore which is great like
记得它 再也 不错了
that's the measure of success when
这是成功时 的措施
people don't remember the thing that you
人们不记得你的事
were trying to replace then you've
我试图取代你
totally won so it was a place to get
完全赢了， 所以这是一个 得到 的地方
answers to programming questions but it
编程问题的答案，但它
wasn't clear if it was like focused Q&A
不清楚它是否像专注的问答
if it was a discussion there were plenty
如果是讨论那就 有很多
of programming forums so we weren't
编程论坛所以我们不是
really sure we were like ok we'll take
真的 知道我们喜欢的同意 ，我们将采取
aspects of Digg and reddit like voting
Digg和reddit等方面的投票
we're very important reordering answers
我们非常重要的重新排序答案
based on votes wiki style stuff of like
基于投票维基风格的东西喜欢
being able to edit post not just your
能够编辑帖子而不仅仅是你的
posts but other people's post to make
帖子，但其他人的帖子
them better and keep them more
他们更好， 并 保持 更多
up-to-date ownership of blogging of like
博客的最新所有权
ok this is me I'm saying this is my
好吧，这 就是我，我说这是我的
voice you know this is the stuff that I
声音， 你知道这是我的东西
know and you know you give your
知道，你知道你给你的
reputation accrues to you and it's pure
声誉积累给你，它是纯粹的
recognition so you asked earlier like
认识所以你早先 问 过像
what motivates programmers I think peer
是什么激励程序员我认为同行
recognition motivates them a lot that
表彰激励他们很多 是
was one of the key insights of Stack
是Stack的关键见解之一
Overflow was like recognition from your
溢出就像你的认可
peers is why things get done initially
同行是最初完成任务的原因
moneyness well your boss but like your
金钱好你的老板，但喜欢你的
peers saying wow this person really
同行真的说这个人哇
knows their stuff has a lot of value so
知道他们的东西 有很多价值所以
the reputation system came from that so
声誉系统 来自 于此
we were sort of frankensteining a bunch
我们有点像弗兰克林一样
of stuff together in Stack Overflow of
Stack Overflow of the stuff中的东西
like stuff we had seen working and we
喜欢我们见过的工作和我们
knew worked and that became Stack
知道工作，这成了堆栈
Overflow and over time we realized it
溢出并随着时间的推移我们实现了 它
wasn't really discussion it was very
真的没有真正讨论它
focused questions and answers there
那里有重点问题和答案
wasn't a lot of room on the page for let
在页面上没有太大的空间 让我们
me talk about this tangential thing it
我谈论 这个切线的事情吧
was more like ok he's an answering
更像是好的，他是一个回答
question is it clarifying the question
问题是它澄清了这个问题
or could it be an alternative answer to
或者它可能是一个替代的答案
the same question because there's
同样的问题，因为有
usually more than one way to do it in
通常不止一种 方式 来做到这一点
program there's
程序就在那里
say five to ten ways and one of the
说五到十的方式和的一个
patterns we got into early on
我们早期进入的模式
stackoverflow was there are questions
stackoverflow有问题
where there would be like hundreds of
那里会有数百个
answers more like Wow
答案更像是哇
how can there be a programming question
怎么会有一个编程问题
with 500 200 500 answers and we looked
我看了 500 200 500个答案
at those we realized those were not
在那些我们意识到那些不是
really questions in the traditional
真的是传统的问题
sense they were discussions it was stuff
感觉他们是讨论它的东西
that we allowed early on that we
我们很早就允许我们
eventually decided wasn't allowed such
最终决定是不允许 这样的
as what's your favorite programming food
什么是你最喜欢的编程食物
you know what's the funniest programming
你知道什么是最有趣的节目
cartoon you've seen and we had to sort
你见过的卡通片，我们不得不排序
of backfill oh into rules about like why
回填 哦成规则关于为什么喜欢
isn't this allowed such as is this a
未在此允许诸如是这样 的
real problem you're facing like nobody
你遇到的真正问题就像没有人一样
goes to work and says wow I can't work
去上班，说：哇，我不能工作
because I don't know what the funniest
因为我不知道最有趣的是什么
programming cartoon is so sorry can't
编程卡通很抱歉不能
compile this code now right it's not a
现在编译这个代码， 它 不是一个
real problem you're facing in your job
你工作中遇到的真正问题
that was run rule and ii like what can
这是运行规则和ii像什么可以
you really learn from that it's like
你真的从中学到了它就像
what i call accidental learning or
我称之为偶然学习或
reddit style learning where you just
reddit的风格学习，你只
acknowledge browse some things
承认浏览一些东西
oh wow you know did you know tree frogs
哇，你知道吗，你知道树蛙吗？
only live three years I mean I just made
只活了 三年，我的意思是我 刚才做的
that up I don't know that's true but uh
那我不 知道 那是真的，但是呃
I didn't really set out to learn that I
我并没有真正开始了解我
don't need to know that right it's an
不需要知道 对 不对这是一个
accidental learning it was more
意外学习更多
intentional learning we were like okay I
有意识的学习我们 就像 我一样
have a problem and I want to learn about
有一个问题，我想了解
stuff around this problem having right
这个问题的问题 是正确的
and it could be theory could be compiler
它可能是理论可以编译
theory it could be other stuff but I'm
理论它可能是其他的东西，但我
having a compiler problem hence I need
因此我需要编译器问题
to know the compiler theory that aspect
要了解编译器理论那方面
of it that gives me the the gets me to
这 让我得到了
my answer right so kind of a directed
我的回答是如此有点直接
learning so we had to backfill all these
学习所以我们不得不回填所有这些
rules as we sort of figured out what the
规则，因为我们想出了什么
heck it was we were doing and the system
哎呀， 我们正在 做的和系统
came very strict over time and a lot of
过来的时间非常严格， 很多
people still complain about that and I
人们仍然抱怨我和我
wrote my latest blog entry what the
写了我 最新的博客 条目是什么
Stack Overflow want to be I wanted to be
Stack Overflow希望成为我想成为的人
when it grows out celebrating the
当它长大庆祝
10-year anniversary yeah yeah so ten
10周年纪念， 是的，所以 十
years and it that system is trended
这个系统是趋势的
towards strictness there's a variety of
严格要求 有各种各样的
reasons for this one is people don't
这一个的原因是人们 没有
like to see other people get reputation
喜欢看到其他人获得声望
for stuff as they view they view as
因为他们认为他们认为的东西
frivolous which I can actually
轻浮，我其实可以
understand because if you saw a program
明白，因为如果你看到一个程序
or got like five hundred up votes for
或者得到 五百张票
funniest programming cartoon or funniest
最有趣的编程卡通或最有趣的
comment they had seen in code it's like
他们在代码中看到的评论就像
well why do they have that reputation is
那么为什么他们有这样的声誉呢
because they wrote the joke probably not
因为他们写这个笑话可能不是
I mean if they did maybe or the cartoon
我的意思是， 如果他们做了或许卡通
right they're getting a bunch of
对，他们得到了一堆
reputation based on someone else's work
基于 别人工作的声誉
that's not even like programming it's
这甚至不像 编程 那样
just a joke right it's a related to
只是一个笑话， 它是一个相关 的
birth so you begin to resent that like
出生 让你开始怨恨 那样
well that's not fair and it isn't at
那是不公平的，也不 是
some level they're correct I mean I
某种程度上他们是正确的我的意思是 我
empathize because like it's not correct
同情，因为它不正确
you get reputation for that versus
你信誉为保证 ， 与
here's a really gnarly
这是一个非常粗糙的
regular expression problem and here's a
正则表达式问题，这里是一个
really you know clever insightful you
真的， 你知道聪明的洞察力
know detailed answer laying out oh
知道详细的答案布局哦
here's why you're seeing the behavior
这就是你看到这种行为的原因
that you're seeing here let me teach you
你在这里看到的 让我教 你
some things about how to avoid that in
关于 如何避免这种情况的一些事情
the future that's that's great like
这就是未来的大 如
that's gold right you want people to
这就是你想要的人的权利金
grab a petition for that not so much for
抓住 请愿书， 而不是那么多
wow look at this funny thing I saw
哇看看 我看到的 这个有趣的 事情
alright great so there's this very
好的， 所以就是这样
specific Q&A format and then take me
具体的问答形式，然后带我
through the journey towards this course
通过这个课程的旅程
in Facebook and Twitter so you start at
在Facebook和Twitter，所以 你开始
the beginning that Stack Overflow
Stack Overflow的开头
evolved to have a purpose so where does
进化到有目的， 所以在哪里
this course this passion you have for
这个课程你有这种激情
creating community for discussion what
创建社区讨论什么
is that when was that born and well part
那是什么时候出生的，很好的一部分
of it is based on the realization the
它是基于 实现的
Stack Overflow is only good for very
Stack Overflow 只对 非常有用
specific subjects where they're sort of
具体科目，其中有几分
it's it's based on data facts and
这是基于数据事实 和
science where answers can be kind of
科学这里的答案可 种
verified to be true another form of that
被证实是另一种形式
is there's the book of knowledge like
有没有像知识这样的书
the tome of knowledge that defines like
定义喜欢的知识的大部头
whatever it is you can refer to that
无论是你可以引用
book and I'll give you the answer there
书，我会在那里给你答案
has to be it only works on subjects
必须是它只适用于主题
where there's like semi clear answers to
那里有半清晰的答案
things that can be verified in some form
可以 用某种形式验证的东西
now again there's always more than one
现在又一次不止一个
way to do it there's complete
做到 这一点的 方法 是完整的
flexibility and system around that but
灵活性和系统围绕着这一点
where it falls down is stuff like poker
它倒下的地方就像扑克一样
and Lego like we had if you go to Stack
和Lego 一样，如果你去堆栈的话
Exchange calm we have an engine that
交换平静，我们有一个引擎
tries to launch different Q&A topics
尝试发布不同的问答主题
right and people can propose Q&A topics
对，人们可以提出问答主题
sample questions and and if he gets
示例问题，如果他 得到了
enough support within the network we
我们在网络内有足够的支持
launch that Q&A site so someone's we
推出Q＆A网站让我们有人
launched where poker and Lego and they
推出了扑克 和乐高以及他们
did horribly right because I mean there
做得非常可怕，因为我的意思是那里
might still be there lingering on in
可能仍然 在 那里挥之不去
some form but it was an experiment this
某种形式，但这是一个实验
is like a test right and some subjects
就像一个考试权和一些科目
work super well in the stack engine and
在堆栈引擎中工作得很好
some don't
有些人没有
but the reason Lego and Poker don't work
但 乐高和扑克不起作用 的原因
is because they're so social really it's
是因为他们真的很社交
not about you know what's the rule here
不是你 知道 这里的规则 是什么
in poker it's like well you know what
在扑克中你很清楚你知道什么
kind of cigars do we like to smoke while
我们喜欢抽烟的那种雪茄
playing poker or you know what's what's
玩扑克或你知道什么是什么
a cool set of cards to use when playing
一套很酷的牌，可以在比赛时使用
poker or you know what some strategies
扑克还是你知道一些策略
like say I have this hand come up with
比如说我有这手提出来
some strategies I could use it's more of
我可以使用的一些策略更多
a discussion around like what's
像是什么一样讨论
happening like with Lego
像乐高一样发生
you know same thing like here's this
你知道同样的事情， 就像这里一样
cool Lego set I found look how awesome
酷乐高集 我发现 看起来多么棒
this isn't like yeah that's freaking
这不是说那是怪异的
awesome right it's not question right
太棒了，这不是问题吧
there's all these social components
所有这些社交组件
discussions that don't fit at all like
讨论根本不适合
we literally have to just allow those in
我们实际上只需要允许那些人
Stack Overflow kids it's not about being
Stack Overflow孩子，这不是关于存在
social it's about
社交它是关于
problems that you're facing in your work
那你面对 你的工作问题，
that you need concrete answers for right
你需要具体的答案
like you have a real demonstrated
就像你有一个真实的证明
problem that's sort of blocking you in
问题的 排序 阻止你
something nobody's blocked by you know
没人知道你被阻止的东西
what should I do when I have a straight
当我有一个笔直的时候该怎么办？
flush right like blocking problem in the
冲洗就像阻塞 问题 一样
world it's just an opportunity to hang
世界它只是 挂 了一个 机会
out and discuss so this course was a way
出去讨论所以这个课程是一种方式
to address that and say look you know
解决这个问题并说 看看你知道
discussion forum software ahead was very
前面的讨论论坛软件非常
very bad and when I came out of Stack
非常糟糕，当我 从 Stack 出来时
Overflow until late or early 20 2013
溢出至2013年末或20年初
2012 it was still very very bad I've
2012年我还是非常非常糟糕
expected it improved and in the four
预计它会在四个方面有所改善
years since I last looked but it had not
我上次看的几年， 但 事实并非如此
improved at all and I was like well
完全改善， 我很好
that's kind of terrible because I love
那种可怕因为我爱
these communities of people talking
这些社区的人 在说话
about things that they love you know
关于 他们爱你的事情
that there's just communities of
那里只有社区
interest right and there's no good
利益权利并没有好处
software for them like startups would
像初创公司那样的软件会
come to me and say hey Jeff I wanna you
来找我，说嘿杰夫，我 想要 你
know I have this startup here's my idea
我知道这个创业公司是我的想法
and the first thing I would say them is
我要说的第一件事就是
like well first why are you asking me
首先，你 为什么 问我
like I don't really know your field
就像我真的不知道你的领域
right let it's necessarily like why
对，让它一定是为什么
aren't you asking like the community
你不是像社区一样问
like the people that are interested in
喜欢有兴趣的人
this problem the people that are using
这个问题 正在使用 的 人
your product why aren't you talking to
你的产品为什么不和你说话
them and then they say Oh a great idea
然后他们说哦，这是个好主意
like how do I do that and then that's
我怎么做那个 然后那就是
when I started playing sad trombone
当我开始演奏悲伤的长号时
because I realized all the software
因为我意识到了所有的软件
involving talking to your users
涉及与您的用户交谈
customers audience patrons whatever it
顾客观众无论如何都是顾客
is it was all really bad you know I was
是不是你知道 我真的很糟糕
like stuff that I would be embarrassed
喜欢我会很尴尬的东西
to recommend to other people and yet
向其他人推荐
that's where I felt they could get the
那是我觉得他们可以得到的地方
biggest and strongest most effective
最大，最有效的
input for what they should be doing with
什么他们应该做的输入
their product right it's from their
他们的产品就是他们的产品
users from their community right that's
来自社区的用户就是这样
what we did on Stack Overflow
我们在Stack Overflow上做了什么
so what we're talking about with forms
所以我们正在谈论表格
the what is it the dark matter of the
该是什么的 暗物质
Internet it's still I don't know if it's
互联网 它仍然是我不知道是不是
still but for a longest time it has some
但是最长的 时间它还有一些
of the most passionate and fascinating
最激情 和 最 迷人的
discussions and what's the usual
讨论和通常的事情
structure there's usually what it's a
结构通常是什么
it's linear so it's sequential it's
它是线性的，所以 它是连续的
you're posting one after the other and
你是一个接一个地张贴的
there's pagination so it's every there's
这是分页所以每一个都有
a 10th post and you go to the next page
第10个 帖子，你转到下一页
and that format still is used by like
和格式仍然是使用像
I'm we're doing a lot of research with
我正在做很多研究
Tesla of vehicles and there's Tesla
特斯拉的车辆和特斯拉
Motors Club forum which is extremely
汽车俱乐部论坛非常
really wanted to run that actually they
真的想要实际运行它们
pinged us about I don't think we got
我们认为 我不 认为我们得到了
but I really would like to gotten that
但我真的很想得到那个
one but they've started before even 2012
一个， 但他们甚至在2012年之前就开始了
I believe I mean they've been running
我相信我的意思是他们一直在 跑步
for a long time it's still an extremely
很长一段时间，它仍然是一个极端的
rich source of information so what
丰富的信息来源 如此
what's broken about that system and how
关于那个系统怎么样？
are you trying to fix it I think there's
你试图解决它 我觉得有吗？
a lot of power in in connecting people
在连接人们方面有很大的力量
that love the same stuff around that
爱围绕 着 同样的东西
specific topic meaning Facebook's idea
具体话题意味着Facebook的想法
of connection is just any human that's
连接只是 任何人类 的
related to another human right like like
与其他人权相关
through friendship or you know any other
通过友谊或你知道任何 其他
reason
原因
Facebook's idea of the world is sort of
世界Facebook的想法是有点
the status update right like a friend of
状态更新就像一个朋友一样
yours did something ate at a restaurant
你的东西在餐馆做了什么
right
对
whereas discussion forums were
而讨论论坛则是
additionally around the interest graph
另外围绕兴趣图
like I love electric cars specifically I
就像我特别爱电动车一样
love Tesla right like I love the way
喜欢特斯拉，就像我爱的那样
they approach the the problem I love the
他们接近我喜欢 的 问题
style of the founder I just love the the
我只是热爱创始人的风格
design ethic there's a lot to like about
设计伦理有很多值得关注的东西
Tesla if you saw the oatmeal he did a
特斯拉，如果你看到他做过的燕麦片
whole love comic to Tesla and it was
整个爱情都喜欢特斯拉 而且它是
actually kind of cool because I learned
实际上很酷， 因为我学到了
some stuff he was some how great Tesla
有些东西他是特斯拉有多么伟大
cars were specifically like how they
汽车特别喜欢它们
were built differently and he went into
他们的建造方式不同，他进入了
a lot of great detail that was really
很多细节 都是真的
interesting to me that oatmeal post if
对我来说有趣的是燕麦片的帖子
you read it is the genesis of pretty
你读到它是 漂亮 的起源
much all interest communities I just
我只是所有兴趣社区
really love this stuff's like for me
真的很喜欢这个东西 对我来说
devilish yo-yos right like I'm into the
恶魔般的溜溜球就像我进入了
yo-yo communities and there's these
溜溜球社区，还有这些
interest communities are just really
兴趣社区才是真的
fascinating to me and I feel more
对我很有吸引力，我感觉更多
connected to the yo-yo communities than
与溜溜球社区有关
I do to you know friends that I don't
我做给你认识的朋友 ，我 不
see that often right like to me that the
看到那个经常对我喜欢的那个
powerful thing is the interest graph and
有趣的是利益图和
Facebook kind of dabbles in the interest
Facebook有点涉嫌利益
graph I mean they have groups you can
图表我的意思是他们有你可以的团体
sign up for groups and stuff but it's
注册团体和 东西， 但它是
really about the relationship graph like
关于 关系图 的确 如此
I'm this is my coworker this is my
我是我的同事，这是我的
relative this is my friend but not so
相对这是我的朋友，但不是这样
much about the interest so I think
很多关于我的兴趣所以我 想
that's the the linchpin of which forums
这是论坛的关键
and communities are built on that I
和社区建立在我身上
personally love like I I like I said
就像我说的那样亲自喜欢我
leadership is about passion right and
领导是关于激情 和 权
being passionate about stuff is is a
对事物充满热情是一种感觉
really valid way to look at the world
真正有效的看待世界的方式
and I think it's a way a lot of stuff in
而且我认为这是 一种很多 东西
the world gets done like I once said
世界变得像我曾经说过的那样完成
someone described me as he's like Jeff
有人形容我像杰夫一样
you're a guy who you just get super
你是一个刚刚变得超级的人
passionate about a few things at a time
热衷于 在时间 的几件事情
and you just go super team from those
而你只是去那些超级团队
things and I was like oh that's kind of
事情和 我一样哦这是 一种
right that's kind of what I do I'll get
对，这就是我所做的一切
into something and just be super into
进入一些东西，只是超级进入
that for a couple years or whatever I
那几年或者其他什么我
just learn all I can about it and go
只是学习所有我可以做的事情然后去
super deep in it and that's how I enjoy
超深的，这就是我的享受
experiencing the world right
体验世界的权利
like not being shallow on a bunch of
就像不是浅浅的一堆
things but being really deep on a few
事情，但真的很少
things that I'm interested in so forums
我对 论坛 感兴趣的事情
kind of unlocked that right and you know
有点解锁，你 知道
you don't want a world where everything
你不想要一个世界的一切
belongs to Facebook at least I don't I
属于Facebook，至少我不是
want a world where communities can kind
想要一个社区 可以善待 的世界
of own themselves set their own norms
自己设定自己的规范
set their own rules control the
设置自己的规则 控制
experience because commit community is
经验，因为提交社区是
also about ownership right like if if
还有关于所有权，如果是的话
you're meeting at the Barnes & Noble
你在Barnes＆Noble会面
every Thursday at Barnes & Noble says
每周四，Barnes＆Noble都说
get out of here you guys don't buy
离开这里，你们不买
enough books well you know you're kind
足够的书你知道你很善良
of hose right Barnes and Noble owns you
右边的Barnes and Noble 软管 拥有你
right like you can't but if you have
就像你不能，但如果你有
your own meeting space you know your own
你知道自己的会议空间
Clubhouse you can set your own rules
会所 你可以自己设定规则
decide what you want to talk about there
决定你想谈 什么
and just really generate a lot better
而且真的生成了很多
information than you could like hanging
信息比 你 想挂的更多
out at Barnes & Noble every Thursday at
每周四在巴恩斯和诺布尔
3:00 p.m. right so that's kind of the
下午3:00 右 所以这是同类产品中
vision of discourse is a place where
话语的视野是一个地方
it's it's fully open source you can take
这是你可以采取的完全开源
the software you can saw it anywhere and
你可以在任何地方看到它的软件
you know you and a group of people can
你知道你和一群人 可以
go deep on whatever it is that you're
深入了解你的一切
into and it this works for startups
进入，这适用于初创公司
right startups are a group of people who
正确的初创公司是一群人
go super deep on a specific problem
深入了解具体问题
right and they want to talk to the
对，他们想和他们谈谈
comedian's like well install this course
喜剧演员喜欢 安装这门课程
right that's what we do at this course
这就是我们在这门课上所做的
that's what I did a stack overflow I
这就是我做了一个堆栈溢出我
spent a lot of time on meta stack
花了很多 时间在元堆栈上
overflow which is our internal well
溢出这是我们内心的好
public community feedback site and just
公共社区反馈网站和公正
experiencing what the users were
体验用户是什么
experiencing right because they're the
体验正确，因为他们是
ones doing all the work in the system
那些在 系统中完成 所有工作的人
and they had a lot of interesting
他们有很多有趣的东西
feedback and there's that 90/10 rule of
反馈和有那 90/10法则
like 90% of the feedback you get is not
比如90％ 的反馈 都不是
really actionable for a variety reasons
因各种原因真的可行
it might be bad feedback it might be
它可能是不好的反馈
crazy feedback it might be feedback you
疯狂的反馈 可能会反馈你
just can't act on right now but there's
只是现在不能采取行动，但有
10% of it that's like gold it's like
它有 10％ 是 像金子 它像
literally gold and diamonds where it's
字面意思是黄金和钻石
like feedback of really good
喜欢非常好的反馈
improvements to your core product that
改进您的核心产品
are not super hard to get to and
并不是很难达到和
actually make a lot of sense and my
实际上使有 很大的意义，我的
favorite is about 5% of those stuff I
我最喜欢的是 那些东西的5％
didn't even see coming it's like oh my
甚至没有看到它就 像是我的
god I never even thought of that but
上帝，我从来没有想过 这一点， 但
that's a brilliant idea
这是个好主意
right and I can point to so many
对，我可以指出这么 多
features of Stack Overflow that we drive
我们开车的Stack Overflow的功能
from metastatic overflow feedback and
从转移溢出反馈和
meta discourse right same exact
元话语同样准确
principle at discourse you know we're
话语中的原则你知道我们是
getting ideas from the comedian's like
从 喜剧演员那里得到想法
oh my god I never thought of that but
哦，天哪，我从未想过那个
that's fantastic right like I love that
这就太棒了，就像我喜欢那样
relationship with the community from
与社区的关系
having built these communities what have
建立了这些社区的东西
you what have you learn about what's the
你有什么了解什么是你的
process of getting a critical mass of
获得临界质量的过程
members in a community is it luck skill
社区中的成员是运气技能
timing persistence what is is it the
持续时间是什么是它 的
tools like discourse that empower that
工具，如话语即授权该
community what what's the key aspect of
社区什么是关键方面
starting
开始
one guy a gal and then building it to
一个人一个加仑，然后建立 它
210 and 100 and a thousand so on I think
我认为 210和100 以及其他一千个
we're starting with an end of one I mean
我的意思 是从一个人的结尾开始
I think it's persistence and and also
我认为这是持久性的 ，也是
you have to be interesting like somebody
你必须 是有趣的人一样
I really admire once that's something
我真的很佩服这件事
that I always liked about blogging he's
我总是喜欢写博客
like here's how you blog you have to
喜欢这里你是如何博客的
have something interesting to say and
有一些有意思的话 和
have an interesting way of saying it
有一种有趣的说法
right yeah and then do that for like 10
是的，然后像10那样做
years so that's the genesis is like you
这样的 起源就像你一样
have to have sort of something
必须要有某种 东西
interesting to say that's not exactly
有趣的 是 ，这并不完全正确
what everyone else is saying and an
别人在说什么和一个
interesting way of saying which is
有趣的说法是哪种方式
another one same kind of entertaining
另一种同样的娱乐
way of saying it and then as far as
这样说的方式然后就此而言
growing it it's like ritual you know
成长它就像你知道的仪式
like you have to like say you're
就像你 必须要说的那样
starting a blog you have to say look I'm
开始一个博客你必须 说我看
gonna blog every week three times a week
每周要写博客三次
and you have to stick to that schedule
你必须坚持 这一时间表
right because until you do that for like
正确的，因为直到你做到 这一点像
several years you're never gonna get
几年你永远不会得到
anywhere like it just takes years to get
任何地方都 需要花费数 年才能获得
to where you need to get to and part of
到你需要 去和部分
that is having the discipline to stick
这是有纪律的坚持
with the schedule and it helps you get
有了时间表，它可以帮助 你
if it's something you're passionate
如果它是你热爱的东西
about this won't feel like work like I
关于这不会 像我 一样工作
love this I could talk about this all
喜欢这个，我可以谈论这一切
day every day right you just have to do
每天都是你必须做的
in a way that's interesting to other
以一种对其他人有趣的方式
people and then as you're growing the
人们，然后随着你的成长
community that pattern of participation
社区的参与模式
within the community of like generating
在像生成的社区内
these artifacts and inviting other
这些文物和邀请其他人
people to help you like collaborate on
人来 帮你喜欢的协作上
these artifacts like even in case of
即使在这种情况下，这些工件也是如此
blogging like I felt in the early days
像我在早期感受到的博客
of my blog which I started 2004 which is
我的博客，我2004年开始 的 这
really the genesis of Stack Overflow if
真的是Stack Overflow的起源if
you look at all my blog it leads up to
你看看我所引导的所有博客
Stack Overflow which was I have all this
Stack Overflow就是我拥有这一切
energy in my blog but I don't like
能量在我的博客但 我不喜欢
40,000 people were subscribing to me and
有40,000人订阅了我和
I was like I want to do something and
我当时想我想要做一些事情，
then then I met Joel and said hey Joel I
然后我遇见了乔尔并说嘿Joel I
want to do something take this ball of
想做点什么拿这个球
energy for my blog and do something and
能量为我的博客和做点什么
all the people reading my blog saw
所有阅读我博客的人都看到了
that's oh cool you're involving us
那真是太酷了 你和我们在一起
you're saying look you're part of this
你说你看起来就是这个的一部分
community let's build this thing
社区让我们建立这个东西
together like they pick the name like we
像他们一样选择像我们这样的名字
voted on the name for Stack Overflow on
投票赞成Stack Overflow的名字
my blog like we came and naming is super
我的博客就像我们来了，命名是超级的
hard first why the hardest problem
努力的第一个为什么是最难的问题
computer science is coming with a good
计算机科学与良好的未来
name for stuff right yeah but there you
是的东西的名称是的但是在那里
can go back to my log there's the poll
可以回到 我的 日志那里是民意调查
where we voted and Stack Overflow became
我们投票的地方和Stack Overflow成了
the name of the site and all the early
网站的名称和所有早期的
beta users are stuck over we're audience
测试版用户被 我们的观众 所 困扰
of my blog plus Joel's blog right so we
我的博客加上Joel的博客，所以我们
started from like if you look at the
从你看的那个开始
Genesis okay I was just a programmer who
创好吧，我只是 一个程序员 谁
said hey I love programming but I have
嘿，我喜欢编程， 但我有
no outlet to talk about it so I'm just
没有谈论它的出路所以我只是
gonna blog about it because I don't have
要写博客 ，因为我 没有
enough people to work to talk to about
有足够的人来工作谈论
it because at the time I worked a place
因为当时我在一个地方工作
where you know programming wasn't the
在那里你知道编程不是
core
核心
output of the company was a
该公司的产量是一个
pharmaceutical company and I just love
制药公司 ，我只是喜欢
this stuff you know to an absurd degree
这个东西你知道的荒谬程度
so I was like I'll just blog about it
所以我就像我只是在博客上谈论它
and then I'll find an audience and
然后我会找到一个观众 和
eventually found an audience eventually
最终发现观众 最终
I found Joel and eventually built Stack
我找到了Joel并最终建立了 Stack
Overflow from that one core of activity
从一个活动核心溢出
right but it was that repetition of
是的，但 重复的是
feeding back in feedback from my blog
从我的博客反馈反馈
comments feedback from Joel feedback
来自Joel反馈的评论反馈
from them the early Stack Overflow
从他们早期的 Stack Overflow
community when people see that you're
社区， 当 人们看到 你的时候
doing that they will follow along with
他们 会这样做
you right they say look cool you're here
你说对了，看起来很酷你就在这里
in good faith you're actually you know
真诚地， 你实际上是你 知道的
not listening to everything because I'm
不 听 一切，因为 我
impossible that's impossible
不可能这是 不可能的
but you're actually you know waiting our
但实际上你知道 等我们的
feedback and what you're doing because
反馈和你正在做的事情，因为
I'm and why wouldn't I because who does
我和我为什么不这样做，因为谁做到了
all the work on Stack Overflow me Joel
Stack Overflow上的所有工作都是Joel
no it's the other programmers that are
没有它的其他程序员是
doing all the work so you gotta have
做所有的 工作，所以你 必须
some respect for that and then you know
一些尊重 ，然后 你知道
discipline around look you know we're
周围的纪律你知道我们是
trying to do a very specific thing here
试图在这里做一个非常具体的事情
on Stack Overflow we're not trying to
在Stack Overflow上我们没有尝试
solve all the world's problems we're
解决我们所有的世界问题
trying to solve this very specific QA
试图解决这个非常具体的质量保证
problem in a very specific way not
问题以非常具体的 方式没有
because we're jerks about it but because
因为我们是关于它的混蛋但是因为
these strict set of rules help us get
这些严格的规则有助于我们获得
really good results right and
真正好的结果吧
programmers that's an easy sell for the
程序员，这是一个容易出售的
most part because programmers are used
大部分是因为 使用了 程序员
to dealing with ridiculous systems of
处理荒谬的系统
rules like constantly that's basically
规则就像经常那样基本上
their job so they're they're very oh
他们的工作让他们 非常好哦
yeah super strict system of rules that
是的，超级严格的规则制度
lets me get on what that's programming
让我得到什么 这是 编程
right that's what Stack Overflow is so
这就是Stack Overflow就是 这样
so you're making it sound easy but in
所以你让它听起来很容易但是 在
2004 let's go back there in 2004 you
2004年，让我们回到那里在2004年 你
started the blog I'm quoting horror was
我引用恐怖的博客开始了
it called that at the beginning at the
它被称为是在开始的
very beginning was one of the smart
一开始就很聪明
things I did it's from a book by Steve
我做的事情来自史蒂夫的一本书
McConnell code complete which is where
McConnell代码完成哪个是 哪里
my favorite programming but still
我最喜欢的编程，但仍然
probably my number one programming book
可能是我的头号编程书
for anyone to read one of the smart
任何人都可以阅读其中一个聪明人
things I did back then I don't always do
我做的事情然后我并不总是这样做
smart things when I start stuff
我开始做东西的时候很 聪明
I contacted Stephen said hey I really
我联系了斯蒂芬 说我真的
like this it was a sidebar illustration
像这样它是一个侧边栏插图
indicating danger in code right coding
指示代码编码中的危险
horror was like watch out and I love
恐惧就像小心一样，我喜欢
that illustration cuz it spoke to me
那个插图 因为它跟我说话
because I saw that illustration go oh my
因为我看到 那个插图 哦我的
god that's me like I'm always my own
上帝，我就像我一直是我自己的
worst enemy like that and a key insight
这样的最大敌人和关键洞察力
and programming is every time you write
每次写作都会编程
something think how am I gonna screw
有些东西想我怎么会搞砸
myself because you will constantly right
我自己， 因为你会永远 正确
so that that icon was like oh yeah I
所以那个图标就像哦，是的，我
need to constantly hold that mirror up
需要经常 持有镜子
and look and say look you're very
看，说看你 很好
fallible you're gonna screw this up like
容易犯错的你会搞砸 像
how can you build this in such a way
你怎么能以这种方式建立这个
that you're not gonna screw it up later
那你 以后不会搞砸了
like how can you
你怎么样？
get that discipline around making sure
得到那个纪律， 确保
at every step I'm thinking through all
我正在思考所有的每一步
the things that I could do wrong or that
那些我可以做错 的事情
other people could do wrong because that
其他人可能会做错，因为那样
is actually how you get to be a better
其实 是 你如何去成为一个更好的
programmer a lot of times right so that
程序员很多次都是这样的
sidebar illustration I loved it so much
侧边栏插图 我非常喜欢它
and I wrote Steve before I started my
我写了史蒂夫 ，我开始之前， 我
belonging say hey can I have permission
归属 说嘿，我可以得到许可
to use this cuz I just really likes
使用这个 我真的很喜欢
illustration and Steve was kind enough
插图和史蒂夫很亲切
to give me a portion to do that and just
给 我一部分去做那件事
continues to give me permission so yeah
继续给我许可所以是的
really that's awesome but in 2004 you
真的很棒， 但在2004年你
started this blog you know you look at
开始这个 你知道你看的 博客
it Stephen King this book on writing or
它 斯蒂芬·金 这本书 的写作或
Steven Pressfield the war of art book I
史蒂文·普雷菲尔德的艺术战书 I
mean it seems like writers suffer I mean
意味着看起来像作家受苦我的意思
it's a hard process of writing write is
写作 是一个艰难的过程
there's gonna be suffering I mean I
会有痛苦我的意思是我
won't kid you like well the work is
不会惹你生气的工作
suffering right like doing the work like
痛苦 就像做工作一样
even when you're every week you're like
即使你每周 都喜欢
okay that blog post wasn't very good or
好吧， 博客文章不是很好或
you know people didn't like it or people
你知道人们不喜欢它 或人
write said disparaging things about it
写下贬低的事情
you have to like have the attitudes like
你必须喜欢有这样的态度
you know no matter what happens I want
你知道无论我想要发生什么
to do this for me right it's not about
对我这样做是 对的， 不是
you it's about me I mean in the end it
你是关于我的，我的意思 是 最终它
is about everyone because this is how
是关于每个人， 因为这是如何
good work gets out into the world but
好的工作进入了世界，但是
you have to be pretty strict about
你必须非常严格
saying like you know I'm selfish in the
说你知道我自私自利
sense that I have to do this for me you
感觉，我要为我做到这一点 你
know you mentioned Stephen King like his
知道你提到斯蒂芬金像 他 一样
book on writing but like one of things I
关于写作的书， 但我喜欢的一件事
do for example when writing is like I
例如， 当写作就像我一样
read it out loud one of the best pieces
大声读出最好的作品之一
of advice for writing anything is read
阅读 任何关于写任何东西的建议
it out loud like multiple times and make
好像多次大声说出来
it sound like you're talking because
这听起来像你在说话，因为
that is the goal of good writing it
这是一个 好写作的 目标， 它
should sound like you said it with with
听起来应该像你说的那样
slightly better phrasing because you
因为你的措辞稍微好一些
have two more time to think about your
还有两次 时间来考虑 你的问题
saying but like it should sound natural
说但是它应该听起来很自然
when you say it and I think that's
当你说出来的时候，我 想是的
probably the single best writing advice
可能是最好的写作建议
and give anyone it's just just read it
并且给任何人它只是阅读它
over and over outloud make sure it
遍地 念Wo 确保它
sounds like something you would normally
听起来像你 通常 会做的事情
say and it sounds good and what's your
说，这听起来不错，你的是什么
process of writing so there's usually a
写作过程 所以通常有一个
pretty good idea behind the blog post so
博客文章背后的好主意
ideas right so I think you gotta have
这些想法是正确的，所以我认为你必须拥有
the concept that there's so many
有这么多的概念
interesting things in the world like I
像我 这样 世界上有趣的事物
mean my god the world is amazing right
意思是，我的上帝， 世界是惊人的 右
like it's you could never write about
喜欢它的，你永远无法写
everything that's going on because it's
一切都在发生，因为它是
so incredible but if you can't come up
如此不可思议，但如果你不能上来
with like let's say one interesting
和 我们说一个有趣的
thing per day to talk about then you're
每天谈论你的事情
not trying hard enough because the world
因为世界 不够努力
is full of just super interesting stuff
充满了超级有趣的东西
and one great way to like mine stuff is
和我最 喜欢的 一个好方法 是
go back to old books because they bring
回到旧书，因为他们带来了
old stuff that's still super relevant
旧的东西，仍然是超级相关的
and I did that a lot because I was like
我做了很多因为我 喜欢
reading classic program books and a lot
阅读经典节目书籍 和 很多
of the early blockbuster like oh I was
像我这样的早期大片
reading this program but can they
阅读这个程序，但他们可以
brought this really cool concept and I
带来了这个非常 酷的概念 和我
want talk about some more and you get
想要谈谈 更多 ， 你得到
the I mean you're not claiming credit
我的意思是你没有声称信用
for the idea but it gives you something
这个 想法，但它给你一些东西
interesting to talk about that's kind of
有趣的是谈论那种
evergreen right like you don't have to
常绿右像你不必
go what should I talk about so just go
我该怎么说 才去吧
dig up some old classic programming
挖掘一些旧的经典编程
books and find something that oh wow
书籍，找到哇哇的东西
that's interesting or how does that
那有趣或者是 怎么回事
apply today or what about X&Y or compare
今天申请或 X＆Y或比较
these two concepts so pull a couple of
这两个概念，从而拉动了几个
sentences from that book and then sort
那本书中的句子然后排序
of play off of it almost reader disagree
几乎没有读者的意见
that so in 2007 you wrote that you were
所以在2007年你写的 是 你
offered a significant amount of money to
提供了大量的资金
sell the blog you chose not to what were
出售你选择的博客不是什么
all the elements you were thinking about
所有你想到的要素
because I'd like to take you back it
因为我想 带你 回到 它
seems like there's a lot of non-linear
好像有很多非线性的
decisions you made through life that's
你通过生活做出的决定
so what was that decision like right so
那么这个决定是怎么回事
i one of the things I love is the choose
我喜欢的一件事就是 选择
your own adventure books which I loved
我喜欢你自己的冒险书
as a kid and I feel like the early
小时候， 我觉得很早
programmer books cuz they're they're all
程序员的书因为他们都是他们的全部
about if-then statements right if this
关于if-then语句是否正确
then this and they're also very very
然后这个，他们也非常非常
unforgiving like there's all these sites
像所有这些网站一样无情
that map the the classic teacher and
映射 经典 老师 和
venture books and how many how comes are
风险书以及有多少是如何实现 的
bad there's a lot of bad outcomes so
坏了， 所以有很多不好的 结果
part of the game is like oh I got a bow
游戏的一部分就像哦，我有一个弓
come go back one step go back on further
来退一万步回去 进一步
steps like how did I get here right like
像我是如何到达这里的步骤一样
it's a sequence of decisions and this is
这是一系列决定，这是
true of life right like every decision
生活就像每个决定一样真实
is a sequence right individually any
是一个单独的任何序列
individual decision is not really right
个人决定是不对的
or wrong but they lead you down a path
或错，但他们引导你走上一条道路
right so I do think there's some truth
对，所以我认为有一些道理
to that so this particular decision the
所以这个特定的 决定
blog II got fairly popular there's a lot
博客II相当受欢迎，有很多
of RSS readers that I discovered and
我发现的RSS阅读器和
this guy contacted me out of the blue
这家伙突然联系了我
from this like bug tracking companies
像这样的bug跟踪公司
like I really want to buy your blog for
就像我真的想买你的博客一样
like I think it was around it was a
就像我认为它周围是一个
hundred thousand dollars when I'm in
我在的时候十万美元
like eighty thousand but it was it was a
像八万，但 它是一个
lot right like and that's you know at
很多就像你知道的那样
the time like I would have a year's
像我一年的时间
worth of salary all at once so I'd
一次性的工资， 所以我
really think about like well you know
真的 好好想想 你知道的
and I remember talking to people the
我记得跟人说过话
times like wow that's a lot of money but
像哇这样的时候很多钱但是
then I'm like I really like my blog
然后我 就像 我真的 喜欢我的博客
right like do I want to sell my blog
就像我想卖我的博客一样
because it wouldn't really belong to me
因为它不 属于我
anymore at that point and one of the
在那 一点上，其中一个
guidelines that I like to I don't like
我喜欢 我不 喜欢 的准则
to give advice to people a lot but one
除了一个人之外，给很多人提供建议
of the piece of advice I do give because
我给出的建议是因为
I do think it's really true and it's
我认为这是 真的 ，而且 确实 如此
generally helpful is whenever you're
通常有用的是随时随地
looking at a set of decisions like
看着像这样的一系列决定
shut you a B or C you got to pick the
关闭 你B或C 你必须选择
thing that's a little scarier in that
这是在一个小东西可怕
list because not you know not like jump
列表， 因为你不知道不喜欢跳
off a cliff scary but the thing that
在悬崖上吓人但事情就是这样
makes you nervous because if you pick
让 你紧张，因为如果你选择
the safe choice it's usually you're not
安全的 选择 通常你不是
really pushing you're not pushing
真的推动你不要推
yourself you're not choosing the thing
你自己不是在选择这个东西
that's gonna help you grow so for me the
这对我来说会帮助你成长
scarier choice was to say no I was like
更可怕的选择是说我不喜欢
well no let's just see where this is
好吧， 不要让我们看看它在哪里
going right because then I own it I mean
走吧， 因为我拥有它， 我的意思是
it belongs to me it's my thing and I can
它属于我，这是我的事 ，我可以
just take it and to some other logical
只是把它和其他一些逻辑
conclusion right because imagine how
结论对，因为想象如何
different the world would've been had I
不同的世界将会 有我
said yes and sold the blog it's like
是的， 并且把博客卖掉了
they're probably gonna be stackoverflow
他们可能会成为 stackoverflow
yeah you know a lot of other stuff would
是的， 你知道很多其他的东西 会
have changed so for that particular
因此而 改变 了
decision I think it was that same rule
决定我 认为这是 同样的规则
like what scares me a little bit more do
喜欢什么让我更害怕
the thing that scares you yeah so
这件事吓到你了
speaking of which startups I think
谈到我认为 哪些初创公司
there's a specific some more general
有一些具体的更一般
questions that a lot of people would be
很多 人都会提出的问题
interested in you've started
对 你的 兴趣 已经开始了
Stack Overflow you started this course
Stack Overflow 你开始了这个课程
so what's the here's one two three guys
那么这里有两三个人
whatever it is in the beginning what was
不管它 起初是什么样的
that process like do you start talking
那个过程就像你开始说话一样
about it do you start programming do you
关于它，你开始编程吗？
start like where is the birth and the
开始就像出生地和地方一样
catalyst that actually I can talk about
实际上我可以 谈论的催化剂
in the context of Oh Stack Overflow and
在 Oh Stack Overflow和 。的背景下
discourse so I think the key thing
话语所以我认为关键的事情
initially is there is a problem
最初是有 问题的
something the some state of the world
某种状态的世界
that's unsatisfactory to the point that
这一点令人不满意
like you're upset about it right like in
就像你对此感到不安一样
that case it was experts exchange I mean
那个案子是专家 交换我的意思
Joel's original idea because I
乔尔最初的想法是因为我
approached I was like look joy I have
走近我很喜欢看快乐我
all this energy by my blog I want to do
所有这些能量都来自我 想做的 博客
something I want to build something but
我想建立一些东西 但是
I don't know what it is because I'm not
我不知道它是什么， 因为我 不是
I'm honestly not a good idea person I'm
老实说，我不是一个好主意的人
really not I'm like the execution guy
真的不是我喜欢执行人
I'm really good at execution but I'm not
我真的擅长执行，但我不是
good at like blue skying ideas not my
擅长蓝色滑行的想法不是我的
forte which is another reason why I like
复地这 是另一个原因 ， 我喜欢
the community feedback because they blue
社区反馈 因为他们是蓝色的
sky all day long for you right so when I
天空整天对你来说都是对的， 所以当我
can just go in and cherry-pick a blue
可以进去 ，樱桃挑选蓝色
sky idea from community even if I have
即使我有社区的天空想法
to spend three hours reading to get one
花三个 小时读 一个
good idea it's worth it man but anyway
好主意，无论如何，这是值得的
so the idea from Joel was hey experts
所以乔尔的想法是嘿专家
exchange
交换
it's got great data but the spirits is
它有很好的数据，但精神是
hideous right it's it's trying to trick
可怕的是它正试图欺骗
you it feels like used-car salesmen it's
你感觉就像二手车销售员一样
just bad so I was like oh that's awesome
只是坏，所以我觉得很棒哦
it feeds in a community it feeds into
它以它所提供的社区为食
like you know we can make a Creative
就像你知道我们可以做一个 创意
Commons so I think the core is to have a
Commons 所以我认为核心是有一个
really good idea that you feel very
真的很好，你感觉非常好
strongly about in the beginning that
强烈关于一开始就 知道
like there's a wrong in the world that
就像世界上有一个错误那样
we will an injustice that we will right
我们将是不公正的，我们将是正确的
through the process of building this
通过建立这个过程
thing for discourse it was like look
话语就像看起来一样
there's no good software for communities
社区没有好的软件
to just hang out
只是闲逛
and like do stuff right like whether
喜欢做的事情就像是否一样
it's problem-solving start up whatever
这是 解决问题 启动任何
forums are such a great building block
论坛是如此伟大的 构建块
or online community and they're hideous
或者在线社区 ，他们很可怕
they were so bad right it was
它们真是太糟糕了
embarrassing like I literally was
像 我 一样尴尬
embarrassed to be associated with this
不好意思与此 相关
software right I was we have to have
软件权利我是我们必须 拥有的
software they could be proud of
他们可以引以为傲的软件
it's like this is competitive with
这就像这是 有 竞争力的
Reddit this is competitive Twitter this
Reddit这是有竞争力的推特
is competitor with Facebook right I
我是Facebook的竞争对手
would be proud to have the software on
我很自豪 能拥有该 软件
my site so that was the genesis of
我的网站所以这就是它的起源
discourse was feeling very strongly
话语感觉非常强烈
about there needs to be a good solution
关于需要一个好的 解决方案
for communities so that's step one
对于社区而言，这是第一步
Genesis why do you feel super strongly
创世纪为什么你感觉超级强烈
about right and then people galvanize
关于正确然后人们激励
around the idea like Joel was already
像 乔尔 这样的想法 已经存在
super excited with the idea I was
对 我 的想法非常兴奋
excited about the idea so with the forum
对论坛 的 想法感到兴奋
software I was posting on Twitter I had
软件我张贴在 Twitter 上 我
research as part of my research I start
我开始研究作为我研究的一部分
researching the problem right and I
正确地研究问题和 我
found a game called forum Wars which was
发现了一款名为“论坛 战争”的游戏
a parody of forum it's still very very
一个模仿论坛它仍然非常非常
funny of like foreign behavior circle
像外国行为圈一样有趣
like I would say 2003 and it's aged some
就像我说的那样2003年它已经老了一些
right like the behavior is a little
这样的 行为 就像 一点点
different in there of Twitter but it was
在推特上有所不同， 但确实如此
awesome it was very funny and it was
真棒这是非常有趣的 ，它是
like a game as like an RPG and it had a
就像一个像RPG一样的游戏而且它有一个
forum attached to it so it was like a
论坛附属于它所以它 就像一个
game about forums with a forum attached
关于论坛附带论坛的游戏
I was like this is awesome right this is
我 觉得这真是太棒了
so cool and the founder of that company
太酷了，那家公司的创始人
or that project it wasn't really a
或者那个项目真的不是
company contacted me this guy Robin Ward
公司联系我这个家伙罗宾沃德
from Toronto's hey you know I saw you
从多伦多嘿，你知道我见过你
been talking about forums and like I
一直在谈论论坛和我一样
really love that problem space he's like
真的很喜欢他喜欢的问题空间
I'd still love to build really good
我仍然喜欢建立真正的 好
forum software cuz I don't think
论坛软件 因为我 不认为
anything out there is any good and I was
什么都没有，我就是
like awesome at that point I was like
就像在 这一点上我很 喜欢 真棒
we're starting a company because like I
我们正在创办一家 公司， 因为和我一样
couldn't have wished for a better person
不可能希望有一个更好的人
to walk through the door and say I'm
走过门 然后说我
excited about this - same thing with Joe
对此感到兴奋- 与乔同样如此
right I mean Joel is a legend in the
右 我的意思是 乔尔是 在 一个传说
industry right so when he walks through
行业权利所以当他 走过时
so I'm excited about as problems like me
所以我对 像我这样的问题 感到兴奋
- man we can do this right so that to me
- 我们可以这样 对待我
is the most important step it's like
是它就像 最重要的一步
having ID you're super excited about and
ID 为 你超级兴奋 和
another person a co-founder right
另一个人是联合创始人的权利
because again you get that dual
因为你再次得到 那个双重
leadership right of like am I making a
领导权就像我做的一样
bad decision sometimes it's nice to have
糟糕的决定有时是不错的
checks of like is this a good idea I
检查喜欢这是一个好 主意我
don't know right so those are the the
不知道对，所以那些 是
crucial seeds but then starting to build
关键的种子，但随后开始建立
stuff whether it's you programmer
无论是程序员还是程序员
there's video types so there's tons of
有视频类型，所以有很多
research there's tons of research like
研究有很多类似的研究
what what's out there that failed
什么在那里 失败了
because a lot of people looked at
因为很多人都看着
successes I look at how successful X's
成功我看看X的成功程度
everybody looks at the successes those
每个人都看着那些成功的人
are boring show me the failures because
很无聊，告诉我失败的原因
that is what's interesting that's where
这就是有趣的地方
people were experimenting that's where
人们正在试验那里的地方
people were pushing but
人们在推动但是
and they failed but they probably failed
他们失败了，但他们可能失败了
for reasons that weren't directly about
由于没有直接的原因
the quality of their idea right yeah so
他们的想法的质量是的， 是的
look at all the failures don't just look
看看所有的失败不只是看
what everybody looks at which is a go
每个人都在看什么是一个去
gosh look at all these successful people
天哪看看 所有这些成功人士
look at the failures look at the things
看看失败看事情
that didn't work research the entire
这 不起作用研究 整个
field and so that's the research that I
领域，这就是 我 的研究
was doing that led me to Robin Wright
在做，导致我罗宾 ·莱特·
was that and then when we for example we
就是那个，然后当我们为例时我们
did Stack Overflow
Stack Overflow
we're like okay well I really like
我很好，我真的很喜欢
elements of voting and Digg and reddit I
投票和Digg和reddit的元素我
like the the Wikipedia everything is up
就像维基百科一切顺利
to date nothing is like an old tombstone
到目前为止 没有什么是像一个老 墓碑
that like has horrible out-of-date
那可怕的已经过时了
information we know that works Wikipedia
我们知道 维基百科的信息
is an amazing resource blogging the idea
是一个惊人的资源博客这个想法
of ownership is so powerful right like
所有权如此强大， 就像
oh I i jo wrote this and look how good
哦， 我写这个 ，看看有多好
Joe's answer is right like all these
乔的答案 就像所有这些一样
concepts were rolling out researching
概念正在进行研究
all the things are out there that we're
所有的事情都在我们身边
working and why they were working and
工作和为什么他们工作和
trying to like fold them into that again
试图再次将它们折叠成那个
that Frankenstein's monster of what
弗兰肯斯坦的怪物是什么
Stack Overflow is and by the way that
Stack Overflow 就是这样的
wasn't a free decision because there's
这不是一个自由的决定，因为有
still a ton of tension in the Stack
堆栈中的压力仍然很大
Overflow system there's reasons people
溢流系统有原因的人
complain about Stack Overflow because
抱怨Stack Overflow 因为
it's so strict right why is it so strict
它是如此严格， 为什么它如此严格
why you guys always closing my questions
为什么你们总是关闭我的问题
it's because there's so much tension
这是因为紧张局势太多了
that we built into the system around
我们内置到系统 周围
like trying to get good good results out
喜欢试图 获得好的结果
of the system and you know it it's not a
系统，你 知道它 不是一个
free that stuff doesn't come for free
免费的东西不是免费的
right it's not like we we're all have
对，这不像我们 都有
perfect answers and nobody will have to
完美的答案，没有人必须
get their feelings hurt or nobody will
让他们的感情受伤或没人会
have to get down voted like that it
不得不 像这样投票
doesn't work that way right like so this
不这样就是这样
is an interesting point a small tangent
小切线 是 一个有趣的 点
yeah you're right about anxiety so I've
是的，你对 焦虑是对的， 所以我
posted a lot of questions and answers on
发布了很多问题和答案
Stack Overflow and the questions I
Stack Overflow 和问题我
usually go to something very specific to
平时去 非常具体 的 东西
something I am working on this is
我正在研究的是这个
something you talk about that really the
你真正谈论的事情
goal of Stack Overflow isn't about is to
Stack Overflow的目标不是关于
write a question not that's not about
写一个不是不是的问题
you it's about the question that will
你是这样一个问题 即会
help the community in the future right
帮助社区 在未来的权利
but that's a tough sell right because
但那是一个艰难的卖权，因为
people are like well you know I don't
人们很喜欢 你知道我没有
really care about the committee what I
真的关心 委员会我 是 什么
care about is my problem my problem and
在乎的 是我的问题，我的问题，
then that's fair right is it sort of
然后那是公平的 权利
that again that tension that balancing
那种紧张就是平衡了
active we want to help you but we also
积极的我们想 帮助你，但我们也
hope that everybody comes behind you
希望 每个人 都支持你
right the long line of people are gonna
对了很长一段路的人都会
come up say oh I kind of have that
来吧说哦，我有点 那样
problem too right and if nobody's ever
问题太 对了，如果没有人
going to come up and say I have this
要上来说我有这个
problem too then that question shouldn't
那个问题也不应该
exist on Stack Overflow because the
存在于Stack Overflow上，因为
question is too specific and that even
问题 太具体而且甚至
that's tension right how do you judge
这是紧张的，你怎么判断
the how do you know that nobody's ever
你怎么知道 没有人永远
gonna have this particular question
会有这个特殊的问题
again so there's a lot of tension in the
再次， 所以有很多 紧张
system do you think that anxiety of
系统你觉得 焦虑
asking the question the anxiety of
问问题的焦虑
answering that tension is inherent to
回答 紧张是固有的
programmers is inherent to this kind of
程序员是这种固有的
process
处理
or can it be improved can be happy land
或者它可以改善可以是幸福的土地
where the that tension is not quite so
那种紧张不是那么紧张的地方
harsh uh I don't think Stack Overflow
苛刻呃我不认为Stack Overflow
can totally change though it works one
可以完全改变，虽然它的作品一个
thing they are working on finally is the
他们最终正在努力的是
ask page had not changed since 2011 I'm
问自2011年以来我没有改变页面
still kind of bitter about this because
仍然有点痛苦，因为
I feel like you have a QA system and
我觉得 你有一个 QA系统
what are the core pages in a KA system
什么是KA系统的核心页面
well first of all the question all the
那么首先这个问题 的 所有
answers and all the also the ask page
答案和所有问题页面
particularly when you're a new user or
特别是当你是一个新用户或
someone trying to ask question that's
有人试图 问的问题这是
the point on what you need the most help
关于你最需要帮助的一点
and we just didn't adapt with the times
我们只是不适应时代
but the good news is they're working on
但 好 消息是他们正在努力
this from what I understand and it's
这是从我的理解和它的
gonna be a more wizard based format and
将是一个更基于向导的格式和
you could envision a world where as part
你可以设想一个世界作为一部分
of this wizard based program when you're
这个基于向导的程序当你的时候
asking questions okay come up with a
提出问题 好吧 想出一个
good title what are good words up in the
好头衔什么是好话
title one word that's not good to put in
标题一个不好放 的词
the title is problem for example I have
标题是问题，例如 我有
a problem oh you have a problem okay a
一个问题哦你有问题 好吗？
problem that's great right like you need
像你需要的那样很好的问题
specifics right like so it's trying to
具体是正确的，所以它 正试图
help you make a good question title for
帮助你成为一个好问题的标题
example that step will be broken out all
例如该步骤将 所有 爆发
that stuff but one of those steps in
这些东西， 但其中一个步骤
that wizard of asking could say hey I'm
那个问的巫师可以说嘿， 我
a little nervous you know I've never
有点紧张你知道我从来没有
done this before can you put me in a
这样做之前 你能把 我 放进 去 吗？
queue for like special mentoring right
排队等特殊指导 权
you could opt into a special mentor I
你可以选择一个特殊的导师 我
think that would be fantastic like I
认为这会像我一样奇妙
don't have any objection to that at all
不带任何 反对 意见
in terms of be an opt-in system because
在 成为一个选择的系统，因为 条款
there are people there like no I just
那里有人不喜欢 我
want to help them I want to help a
想帮助他们我想帮助他们
person no matter what I want to go above
不管 我想要 去哪个人
and beyond I want to spend like hours
而且我想花几个小时
with this person uh Ben's what their
和这个人 呃Ben是他们的
goals are right a great idea Who am I to
目标是对的好主意我是谁
judge right so that's fine it's not
判断正确， 这样就没事了
precluded from happening but there's a
排除了发生但是有一个
certain big-city ethos that we started
我们开始的某些大城市风气
with like look we're of New York City
看起来我们是纽约市
you don't come to New York City and
你不来纽约 市
expect them to be Oh welcome to the city
期待他们欢迎 来到这座城市
Joe how's it going come on in let me
乔怎么样才能让我这么做
show you around
带你四处看看
that's not how New York City works right
这不是纽约市如何运作的
I mean and you know again New York City
我的意思是 ，你又 知道了 纽约市
is a reputation for being rude which I
我是一个粗鲁的名声
actually don't think it is having been
实际上并不认为它已经存在
there fairly recently it's not rude
最近，它并不粗鲁
people are just like going about their
人们就像去做他们的
business right now look look I have
现在的生意看起来 我有
things to do I'm busy I'm a busy
要做的事情我很忙，我很忙
professional as are you
和你一样专业
and since you're a busy professional
因为你是一个忙碌的专业人士
certainly when you ask a question you're
当然，当你问 你 一个问题
gonna ask the best possible question
要问最好的问题
right because you're a busy professional
对，因为你是一个忙碌的专业人士
and you would not accept anything less
你不会接受任何更少的东西
than a very well waiting question with a
而不是一个非常好的 等待问题
lot of detail about why you're doing it
关于 你为什么 这么做的 很多 细节
what you're doing what you researched
你正在做什么研究
what you found right because you're a
你找到了什么， 因为你是一个
professional like me right and this rubs
像我一样的专业人士，这是摩擦
people sometimes the wrong way and I
人们有时候错误的方式和我
don't think it's wrong to say look I
不要认为看我是不对的
don't want that experience I want just a
不想要我想要的体验
more chill place for beginners and I
对于初学者和我来说更加寒冷的地方
still think sacrifice is not was never
仍然认为牺牲不是永远不会
designed for beginners right there's
专为初学者设计的
this misconception that you know even
这种误解， 你甚至不知道
Joel says some - oh yes deck overflow
乔尔说了一些 - 哦是甲板溢出
for beginners and I think if you're a
对于初学者， 我想如果你是一个
prodigy it can be all right but that's
神童可以没事，但那就是
not not really representative right like
不是没有真正代表性的
I think as a beginner you want a totally
我认为作为初学者，你完全想要一个
different set of tools you want like
你想要的不同工具集
live screen sharing live chat you want
实时屏幕共享 你想要的 实时聊天
access to resources you want a
访问您想要 的 资源
playground like a playground you can
你可以在游乐场玩耍
experiment in and like test and all this
实验和 测试 一样 ， 这 一切
stuff that we just don't give people
东西， 我们 只是不 给人家
because that was never really the the
因为这是从来没有真正 的对
audience that we were designing the
我们正在设计的观众
second true flow for that doesn't mean
第二个真正的流程 并不意味着
it's wrong and I think it would be
这是错的，我认为会是这样
awesome if there was a site like that on
如果真棒有这样的网站 上
the internet or if stack overlies and
互联网或堆栈 覆盖和
hey you know we're gonna start doing
嘿，你知道我们会开始做的
this that's fine too you know I'm not
这很好，你知道我不是
there I'm not making those decisions but
在那里，我没有做出那些决定
I do think the pressure the tension that
我认为压力的张力
you describe is there for people to be
你描述的是 人们的存在
look I'm a little nervous cuz I know I
看起来我有点紧张， 因为我知道我
gotta do my best work right the other
要做到最好，另一个做得最好
one is something you talk about which is
一个是你说说 这是一件好事
also really interesting to me is
我真的很有意思
duplicate questions or do it's a it's a
重复的问题或做它是一个
really difficult problem that you
你真的很难的问题
highlight super far is super hard like
突出超级远是超级喜欢
you could take one little topic and you
你可以 拿一个小话题 和你
could probably write 10 20 30 ways of
可能会写10 20 30种方式
asking about that topic and there will
询问那个话题并且会有
be all different I don't know if there
是不同的我不 知道是否有
should be one page that answers all of
应该是一个回答所有问题的页面
it is there a way that Stack Overflow
它有一种 Stack Overflow方式
can help disambiguate like separate
可以帮助消除歧义，如分开
these duplicate questions or connect
这些重复的问题或连接
them together or is it a totally
他们在一起还是完全
hopeless difficult impossible task I
无望的艰难任务我
think it's a very very hard computer
认为这是一台非常非常难的电脑
science problem and partly because
科学问题，部分是因为
people are very good at using completely
人们 非常善于 完全使用
different words it always amazed me on
不同的 话它总是 让我吃惊的
Stack Overflow you'd have two questions
Stack Overflow你有两个问题
that were functionally identical and one
在功能相同 和一个
question had like zero words in common
问题就像零言辞一样
with the other question like oh my god
另一个问题就像哦，我的上帝
from a computer science perspective how
从计算机科学的 角度来看如何
do you even begin to solve that and it
你甚至开始 解决它和它
happens all the time people are
人们一直都在发生
super-good at this right accidentally at
不小心 擅长这个 权利
asking the same thing in in like in 10
在 10中问同样的事情
20 different ways and the other
20 种不同的方式和另一种
complexity is we want some of those
复杂性是我们想要一些那些
duplicates to exist because if there's
重复存在因为如果存在的话
five versions with different words have
有五个 不同单词的 版本
those five versions point to the one
这五个版本指向一个版本
centralized answer right it's like okay
集中回答吧就好了
this is duplicate nope no worries this
这是重复的不，不用担心这个
here's here's the answer that you wanted
这里是你 想要 的答案
over here on this this this you know the
在此， 你知道这个
prime example that we want to have
我们 想要的 主要例子
rather having ten copies of the question
而是有十个 问题的 副本
and the answer because if you have 10
和答案，因为如果你有 10
copies of the question the answer this
这个 问题的 答案副本
also devalues the reputation system
也贬低了声誉 系统
which programmers hate as I previously
哪个程序员像我以前一样讨厌
mentioned you're getting reputation for
提到你的声誉
an answer that somebody else or engaged
别人 或订婚的答案
it's like well it's an answer but
它就像是一个答案，但是
somebody are sorry gave that answer so
有人很抱歉给了 答案
why are you getting reputation for the
为什么你会获得声誉
same answer as the other guy who gave it
与给予 它 的另一个人相同的答案
4 years ago people get offended by that
4 年前人们为此感到生气
right so the reputation system itself
这是声誉 系统本身
adds tension to the system in that the
增加了对系统的紧张感
people who have a lot of reputation
有很多 声誉的人
become very incentivized to enforce the
变得非常激励去执行
reputation system and for the most part
声誉系统 ， 大部分
that's good I know it sounds weird but
这很好我知道这听起来很奇怪 但是
for most parts like look strict systems
对于大多数部件，如严格的系统
I think to use Tec powerful you have to
我认为使用 Tec功能强大
have the idea that ok strict systems
认为ok严格的系统
ultimately work better and I do think in
最终工作得更好，我确实想到了
programming you're familiar with loose
编程你熟悉松散
typing versus strict typing right the
打字与严格指定权
idea that you can declare a variable not
想法， 你可以声明一个变量不
declare a variable rather you start
声明一个变量而不是你开始
using a variable and ok I see it's
使用变量 ，好吧我看到了
implicitly an integer BAM awesome
隐式地，整数BAM 很棒
duck equals 5 well duck is now an in
鸭子等于5井鸭子现在是一个
under 5 right and you're like cool
在5岁以下，你就像 很酷
awesome simpler right why would I want
真棒更简单，为什么我想要
to worry about typing and for a long
担心打字和长时间
time like in the Ruby community they're
他们是Ruby社区的时间
like yeah this is awesome like you just
就像是的， 这 就像你一样 真棒
do a bunch of unit testing which is
做一堆单元测试
testing your programs validity after the
在测试你的 程序有效性之后
fact to catch any bugs that that strict
事实上，抓住任何严格的错误
typing of variables would have caught
变量的输入会被抓住
and now you have this thing called
现在你有这个叫做的东西
typescript from Microsoft from the guy
来自微软的打字稿
who built c-sharp Manders who's one of
谁建立了C-sharp Manders谁是其中之一
the greatest minds in software
软件中最伟大的头脑
development right like in terms of
发展权就像
language design and says no no no we
语言设计，并说不，不，我们
want to bolt on a strict type system to
想要严格的类型系统
JavaScript because it makes things
JavaScript， 因为它制造的 东西
better and now everybody's like oh my
更好，现在每个人都喜欢哦我的
god we we deployed typescript and found
上帝，我们部署了打字稿 并找到了
50 latent bugs that we didn't know about
50个 我们不知道的潜在错误
right like this is super common so I
这样的权利 是非常普遍的 所以我
think there is a truth in programming
认为编程有一个道理
that strictness it's not the goal we're
严格， 这不是我们的目标
not saying be super strict cuz
不是说超级严格 因为
strictness is correct no it's no no
严格是正确的， 不，不，不
strictness produces better results
严格会产生更好的结果
that's what I'm saying right so strict
这就是我说的 那么严格
typing of variables I would say you
输入变量我会说你
almost universally have consensus now is
现在几乎普遍有共识
basically correct should be that way in
基本上应该是正确 的
every language right duck equals 5
每种语言 右鸭等于 5
should
应该
during an error because you know you
在错误期间，因为你认识你
didn't clear you didn't tell me the duck
没有说清楚你 没有告诉我鸭子
was an integer right that's a bug right
是一个整数 权利，这是一个错误的权利
or maybe you missed time you typed deck
或者你错过了 打字牌的 时间
right instead of duck right you never
对，而不是对你从来没有
know this happens all the time right so
知道这一切发生的时候对 好
with that in mind I will say that the
考虑到这一点 我 会说的
strictness the system is correct now
严格，系统现在是正确的
that doesn't mean cruel
这并不意味着残忍
that doesn't mean mean that doesn't mean
这并不意味着意味着并不意味着
angry it just means tricked okay so I
生气它只是意味着欺骗 好吧所以我
think where there's misunderstanding is
想想哪里有误解
and people get cranky right like another
人们变得像 另一个人一样胡思乱想
question you asked is like why are
你问的问题就像是为什么
programmers kind of mean sometimes well
程序员有时意味着很好
who'da programmers work with all day
谁是程序员一整天都在工作
long so I have a theory that if you're
所以我有一个理论， 如果你是
at a job and you work with assholes all
在工作 ，你有蛀虫 所有 工作
day long
一整天
what do you eventually become an asshole
你最终会成为一个混蛋
an asshole and what is the computer
一个混蛋，什么是电脑
except the world's biggest asshole
除了世界上最大的混蛋
because the computer has no time for
因为 电脑没时间
your the computer the minute
你的胡扯计算机一分钟
you make a mistake everything else
其他一切都 弄错了
crashing down right one semicolon has
右边的一个分号崩溃了
crashed space missions right so that's
坠毁的太空任务就是这样
normal
正常
so you begin to internalize that you
所以你开始内化你
begin to think oh my coworker the
开始 想噢，我 的 同事
computer is super strict and kind of a
计算机是超级严格 类型的
jerk about everything so that's kind of
关于一切的混蛋，这就是那种
how I'm gonna be because I work with
我将如何成为因为我合作
this computer and I have to accede to
这台电脑和我必须 加入
its terms on everything so therefore you
它的所有条款因此你
start to absorb that and you start to
开始吸收那个，你就开始了
think oh well being really strict
认为哦，真的很严格
arbitrarily is really good an error of
任意的确是一个很好的错误
error code five six two four nine is a
错误代码五六 二四有九是一个
completely good error message because
完全不错的错误消息因为
that's what the computer gave me right
这就是电脑给我的权利
so you kind of forget to be a person at
所以你有点忘了成为一个人
some level and you know they say great
某种程度 ，你 知道他们说得很好
detectives internalized criminals and
侦探内化犯罪分子和犯罪分子
kind of are criminals themselves like
有点像罪犯一样
this trope of the master detective is
这位大师级侦探的比喻是
good because you can think like the
好，因为你可以 这样思考
criminal well I do think that's true of
犯罪很好我认为这是真的
programmers really good programmers
程序员真的很好的程序员
think like the computer because that's
像计算机一样思考，因为那是
their job but if you internalize it too
他们的工作， 但如果你内化它
much you become the computer you become
很多你成为你成为的电脑
a kind of become a jerk to everybody
对所有人来说都是一种混蛋
because that's what you've internalized
因为这就是你内化的东西
you're almost not a jerk but you have no
你几乎不是一个混蛋， 但你没有
patience for a lack of strictness as you
对你 缺乏 严格的耐心
said it's not out of a sense of meanness
说这不是出于一种卑鄙的感觉
it's accidental but I do believe it's an
这是偶然的，但我相信它是一个
occupational hazard of being a
的 是 一个职业危险
programmer is you start to behave like
程序员你开始表现得像
the computer you're very unforgiving
电脑你是非常无情的
you're very terse you're very Oh wrong
你非常简洁，你非常错哦
and correct move on it's like well can
并且正确地移动 就好了
you help me like what could I do to fix
你帮助我，我 可以做些什么来解决
now wrong say next question right like
现在 错了 说下一个问题 就好了
that's normal for the computer right
这是 正常的电脑 右键
just fail next right like out of you
就像在你身边一样失败
remember in Saturday Night Live like in
请记住在周六夜生活中
the nine
九
they had this character was an IT guy
他们有这个角色 是一个IT人
yeah the move guy move was that Jimmy
是的，那个移动的家伙是 Jimmy
Fallon no no can't play dumb okay yeah I
法伦没有不能发挥愚蠢 好吧是的我
remember move right he had no patience
记得向右移动他没有耐心
for he might have been MADtv actually
因为他可能实际上 是 MADtv
might have been might a bit but anyway
可能有点可能但是无论如何
that was the that's always been the
那是一直以来的
perception right you start to behave
感觉正确，你开始表现
like the computer it's like oh you're
就像电脑一样哦， 你是
wrong out of the way you know you've
你不知道自己的错误
written so many blog posts about
约写了这么多的博客文章
programming about programs programming
关于程序编程的编程
programmers what do you think makes a
程序员 你觉得怎么样？
good let's start with what makes a good
好吧，让我们从创造好的东西开始吧
solo programmer well I don't think you
独奏程序员我不认为 你
should be a solo programmer I think to
应该是我认为的独奏程序员
be a good solo programmer it's kind of
是一个很好的独奏程序员它是一种
like what I talked about well not on mic
就像我在 麦克风 上谈论的那样
but one of the things john carmack one
但约翰卡马克 的事情 之一
of the best points he makes in the book
他在书中提出的最佳观点
masters of doom which is a fantastic
厄运的主人是一个太棒了
book anybody listening this who hasn't
预订任何听过 这个没有的人
read it please read it's such a great
阅读它， 请阅读它是如此的伟大
book is that at the time they were
这本书 是他们当时的
working on stuff like Wolfenstein and
研究像Wolfenstein和
doom like they didn't have the resources
厄运就像他们没有 资源一样
that we have today they didn't have
我们 今天他们没有
Stack Overflow they didn't have
Stack Overflow他们没有
Wikipedia they didn't have like
维基百科他们没有喜欢
discourse forums they didn't have places
话语论坛他们没有地方
to go to get people to help them write
去 让人们去帮助他们 写
they had to work on their own and that's
他们必须自己工作，那就是
why it took a genius like Carmack to do
为什么像Carmack这样的天才呢？
this stuff because you had to be a
这个东西，因为你必须是一个
genius to invent from first principles a
从第一原则发明的天才a
lot of the stuff he was he was like the
很多 东西他是 他很喜欢的
hacks he was coming up with were genius
黑客，他想出 了天才
right genius level stuff but you don't
正确的天才级别的东西，但你没有
need to be a genius anymore and that
需要 成为一个天才和那个
means not working by yourself you have
意味着不通过自己的工作，你 有
to be good at researching stuff online
善于在线研究
you have to be good at asking questions
你必须擅长提问
really good questions that are really
真的很好的问题
well researched which implies oh I went
研究得很好，这意味着我 去了
out and researched for three hours
出去研究了三个小时
before I wrote those questions like
在我写这些问题之前
that's what you should be doing because
那是你应该做的，因为
that's what's gonna make you good write
这就是让你 写得 好的东西
to me this is the big difference between
对我来说这是 两者之间 的巨大 差异
programming in like the 80s versus
编程与80年代相比
programming today is like you you kind
今天的编程就像你善良
of had to be by yourself back then like
的必须是 自己当时像
where would you go for answers I
你会在哪里寻找答案 我
remember in the early days when I was a
在早期记得当我 还是一个
learning Visual Basic for Windows like I
像我一样学习Visual Basic for Windows
would call the Microsoft helpline on the
将呼吁微软热线
phone when I had like program because I
我喜欢节目的电话， 因为我
was like I don't know what to do so I
就像我不知道该怎么做，所以我
would like go and call and they have
愿 去打电话，他们有
these huge phone banks and like can you
这些巨大的手机银行和你一样
imagine how alien that is now like who
想象现在的外星人是 谁
would do that right like that's crazy
会做那样的，就像疯了一样
so there was just nowhere else to go
所以别无处可去
when you got stuck right like I had the
当你像我一样被卡住了
books that came with it I read those
随附的书我读了这些
study those religiously I I just saw a
虔诚地研究那些我只是看到了一个
post from Steve Sinofsky that said this
Steve Sinofsky的帖子说这个
C++ version seven
C ++版本七
came with like 10,000 pages of written
有10,000页写的
material because where else were you
材料，因为你在哪里
gonna figure that stuff out go to the
要想出那些东西去 了
library I mean you don't have what
图书馆我的意思是你 没有什么
capito you didn't have you know read it
capito你不知道你读过它
you know were to go to answer these
你知道要去回答这些问题
questions so you you've talked about
问题 所以你已经谈过了
through the years basically not having
经过多年基本上没有
an ego and not thinking that you're the
一个自我，而不是认为你是谁
best programmer in the world it's always
这是 世界上最好的程序员
kind of just looking to improve to
那种只是 希望提高
become a better programmer than you were
成为比你更好的程序员
yesterday so how have you changed as a
昨天你怎么改变 了
programmer and as a as a thinker
程序员和思想家
designer around programming over it'll
设计师围绕它编程
past what is it 15 years really of being
过去15年 真实存在的 是什么
a public figure I would say the big
一个公众人物，我 会 说大
insight that I had is eventually as a
我的洞察力最终是作为一个
programmer you have to kind of stop
程序员你必须停下来
writing code to be effective which is
编写有效的 代码
kind of disturbing because you really
有点令人不安， 因为你真的
love it and but you realize like being
喜欢它，但你意识到自己 喜欢
effective at program at programming in
在编程方面有效
the general sense doesn't mean writing
一般意义并不 意味着写作
code and a lot times you can be much
代码和大量的 时间，你可以 多
more successful by not writing code and
不写 代码更成功
writing code in terms of just solving
编写代码只是解决问题
the problems you have essentially hiring
你基本上招聘的问题
people that are really good and like
人是 非常 好，喜欢
setting them free and like giving them
让他们自由，喜欢给他们
basic direction right like on strategy
基本 方向 就像战略一样
and stuff because a lot of the problems
和东西 因为很多 问题
you encounter aren't necessarily solved
你遇到的不一定解决
through like really gnarly code they're
通过像他们真正粗糙的代码一样
solved by conceptual solutions which can
通过可以的概念解决方案解决
then be turned into code but are you
然后变成 代码，但是你
even solving the right problem I mean so
甚至解决正确的问题我的意思是这样
I would say for me the main insight I
我会对我说主要见解
have is to succeed as a programmer you
我是成功的程序员
eventually kind of stop writing code
最终有点 停止编写代码
that's gonna sound discouraging probably
这听起来可能令人沮丧
to people hearing but I don't mean it
人们听到但我不是故意的
that way what I mean is that you're
这就是我的意思是你是
coding at a higher level language
以更高级别的语言编码
eventually like okay so we're coding an
最终还好，所以我们正在编码
assembly language right that's the
汇编语言就是这样的
beginning right you're hard coded to the
从右开始你就是 硬编码的
architecture then you have stuff like
建筑那么你有类似的东西
see we're cool we can abstract across
看到我们很酷，我们可以抽象出来
the architecture you can write code I
你 可以编写 代码的架构我
can then compile that code for arm or
然后可以编译 arm或的 代码
you know you know whatever you know x86
你知道你知道什么x86
or whatever else is out there and then
或任何其他在那里 ，然后
even higher level net right like you're
甚至更高级别的净 权利就像你一样
looking like Python Ruby interpreted
看起来像Python Ruby解释
languages and then to me as a programmer
语言，然后作为程序员
like okay I want to go even higher
好吧我想要 更高
I want to go higher than that how do I
我想要比我更高
abstract higher than the language it's
抽象高于它的语言
like well you abstract in spoken
就像你用口语抽象一样
language and written language right like
语言和书面语等
you're sort of inspiring people to get
你有点启发 人们得到
things done giving them guidance like
事情做好给他们 指导， 像
what if we did this what if we did this
如果我们这样做会怎么做呢？
you're writing in the highest level
你写的 是最高级别的
language that there is
语言有
which is for me English right whatever
无论如何 ，这对我来说都是英语
your spoken language is so it's all
你的口语就是这样
about being effective right and I think
关于有效的 权利，我认为
a patrick mckenzie Patio 11 on Hacker
黑客 帕特里克·麦肯齐天井11 号
News and works at stripe has a great
条纹的新闻和作品非常棒
post about this of how calling yourself
关于如何称呼自己的帖子
a programmer is a career limiting move
程序员是职业限制性举措
at some level once you get far enough
一旦你走得足够远，在某种程度上
from your crin I really believe that and
从你的 crin我真的相信 和
again I apologize this is sound
我再次道歉这是合理的
discouraging I don't mean it to be but
令人沮丧的我不是这个意思 的，但却
he's so right because all the stuff that
他是因为所有的东西 ，所以正确的
goes on around the code like the people
像人一样围绕代码
mm-hmm like that's another thing if you
mm-hmm 就像你这样的另一件事
look at my early blogging piece is about
看看我早期的博客文章是关于什么的
Wow
哇
programming is about people more than
编程是关于人而 不是
it's about code which doesn't really
它是关于代码而不是真的
make sense right but it's about can
有意义，但它是关于可以
these people even get along together can
这些人甚至可以相处在一起
they understand each other can you even
他们甚至可以相互理解
explain to me what it is you're working
向我解释一下你在做什么
on are you solving the right problem
你在解决正确的问题吗？
people weren't right another classic
人们不是另一个经典
programming book which again up there
编程书再次出现在那里
with code complete please read people
代码完整请阅读人
where it's that software is people right
哪个软件是人的权利
people are the software first and
人是软件的第一 而且
foremost so a lot of the skills that I
最重要的是我的很多技能
was working on early on the blog were
正在早期 的博客上工作过
about figuring out the people parts of
关于弄清楚 人们的 一部分
programming which were the harder parts
编程哪些是更难的部分
the hard part of programming once you
编程的难点一旦你
get to a certain skill of in programming
获得编程 的某种 技能
you can pretty much solve any reasonable
你几乎可以解决任何合理的问题
problem that's put in front of you
放在你面前的问题
you're not writing algorithms from
你不是在编写算法
scratch right that just doesn't happen
划伤， 这是不会 发生的
so any sort of reasonable problem for in
所以任何合理的问题
front of you're gonna be able to solve
在 你 面前 你 将 能够解决
but what you can't solve is our manager
但你不能解决的是我们的经理
is a total jerk you cannot solve that
是一个你无法解决的混蛋
with code that is not a codes problem
代码 不是代码 问题
and yet that will cripple you way more
然而，这将使你更加瘫痪
than oh we had to use this stupid
哦，我们不得不 使用这个愚蠢的
framework I don't like or or you know
框架我不喜欢或者你知道
Sam keeps writing bad code that I hate
Sam一直在编写我讨厌的错误代码
or you know you know Dave is off there
或者你知道你知道戴夫在那里
in the wilderness writing god knows what
在荒野写作上帝知道什么
right these are not your problems your
这些不是你的问题
problems your manager or a co-worker is
问题你的经理 或同事 是
so toxic to everybody else in your team
对 团队中的 其他人都有毒
that like nobody can get anything done
就像 没有人能做任何事情一样
because everybody's so stressed out and
因为每个人都如此强调 和
freaked out right these are the problems
吓坏了， 这些 都是问题所在
that you have to attack absolutely and
你必须 绝对攻
so as you go to these higher level
所以你去这些更高的水平
abstractions as you developed as a
你开发的抽象概念
programmer to higher higher level
程序员到更高的水平
abstractions go into natural language
抽象进入自然语言
you're also the guy who kind of preached
你也是那种鼓吹的人
you know building it you know diving in
你知道建造它， 你知道潜水
and doing it and and and like learn by
并且这样做并且并且喜欢学习
doing yes do you do you worry that as
你做的是 ，你担心吗？
you get to higher higher level
你达到更高的水平
abstractions
抽象
you lose track
你失去了轨道
of the lower level of just building is
刚建筑的下层是
like do you worry about that you know
像你担心 ， 你知道
even not maybe now but 10 years from now
甚至不是现在，但是 从 现在起 10年
20 years from now well no I mean there
从 现在开始 20 年， 我的意思不是
is always that paranoia and oh gosh I
永远是那种偏执狂 哦天啊
don't feel as valuable since I'm not
因为我不是，所以 不觉得 有价值
writing code but for me like when we
编写代码但对我来说就像我们一样
started the discourse project it was
开始了它的话语项目
Ruby which I didn't really know Ruby I
红宝石，我真的不 知道 我 的Ruby
mean as you pointed out and this is
正如你指出的那样，这就是
another valuable have straight from
另一个有价值的直接来自
Stack Overflow you can be super
Stack Overflow 你可以超级
proficient for example C sharp which I
精通例如C sharp我
was working in that's what we built
在正在这就是 我们建
Stack Overflow and and still is written
Stack Overflow和仍然是写的
in and then switch to Ruby and you're a
然后切换到Ruby， 你就是了
newbie again right like I'm but but you
新手再次正确，就像我，但你
have the framework I know what a for
有框架，我知道什么是
loop is I know what recursion is I know
循环是我知道我知道什么递归
you know what would attract a stack
你知道什么 会吸引一堆
traces right like I have all the
追踪就像我拥有的​​一样
fundamental concepts to be a programmer
作为程序员的基本概念
I just don't know Ruby so I'm still on a
我只是不知道红宝石，所以我仍然在
higher level I'm not like a beginner
更高的水平我不像初学者
beginner like you're saying I'm just
初学者就像你说我只是
like I need to apply my programming
就像我需要 应用我的编程
concepts I already know to Ruby what so
概念我已经知道红宝石什么，所以
there's a question that's really
有一个问题是真的
interesting so looking at Ruby how do
有趣 所以看看Ruby怎么做
you go about learning enough that your
你去学习足够的知识
intuition can be applied well that
直觉可以应用于清楚
carryover that's all trying to get to is
所有尝试去的遗留物 都是
like what I realized written when I
像我 意识到写 什么 ，当我
started was just me and Robin I realized
开始只是我 和罗宾我意识到
if I bother Robin I am now costing us
如果我打扰罗宾， 我 现在要付钱给我们
productivity right every time I go to
每次 去的 时候，生产力都是正确的
Robin rather than building the the are
罗宾，而不是建立在 的 是
our first alpha version of this course
我们这个课程的第一个alpha版本
he's now answering my stupid questions
他现在正在回答我的愚蠢问题
about Ruby is that a good use of his
关于Ruby是一个很好 用的他
time is that a good use of my time
时间就是 好好利用我的时间
the answer to both of those was
两者的答案都是
resoundingly no right like we were
像我们一样，没有权利
getting to an alpha and it was a pretty
得到一个阿尔法，这是一个漂亮的
much disk ok we'll hire more programmers
很多 磁盘 我们会聘请更多的程序员
right like we eventually hired Neil and
就像我们最终聘请尼尔 和
then eventually Sam who came in as a
然后最终萨姆作为一个进来
co-founder actually was Sam first then
联合创始人 实际上当时是Sam
Neil later but the answer of the problem
尼尔后来但问题的答案
is just hire other competent programmers
只是聘请其他有能力的程序员
it's not like teach now I shalt pull
现在我不喜欢教我拉
myself up by my bootstraps and Ruby but
我自己的引导 和Ruby，但是
at some point writing code becomes a
在某些时候编写代码成为一个
liability to you in terms of getting
在 获得 方面对您 负有责任
things done there's so many other things
做的 事情 还有很多其他的 事情
that go on in the project like building
在项目中继续像建筑一样
the prototype like you mentioned like
就像你提到的原型一样
well how do you if you're not writing
如果你不写作，你怎么样？
code has every keep focus on like what
代码一直都在关注什么
what are we building well first basic
什么是我们建立 良好的第一基础
mock-ups and research right like what
模拟和研究就像什么
what do we even want to build there's a
什么，我们甚至想建 有一个
little bit of that that goes on then
的那一点点是 点亮后
very quickly get to the prototype stage
很快进入原型阶段
like build a prototype
喜欢建立一个原型
let's iterate on the prototype really
让我们真的迭代原型
really rapidly that's what we do at this
真的很快 就是我们 在这 做 的事情
course and that's what we we demoed to
当然，这 就是我们 演示的内容
get our seed funding for this course was
获得我们为这门课程提供的种子资金
the the alpha version of discourse that
话语的alpha 版本
we had running and ready to go and it
我们已经跑步了 ，准备出发了
was very it was bad
非常 糟糕
I mean it was I'll just tell you it was
我的意思是我只是告诉你它
bad I have we have screenshots and I'm
糟糕， 我有截图，我是
just like embarrassed to look at it now
就像现在看它一样尴尬
but it was the prototype we were
但 它是我们的原型
figuring out like what's working what's
弄清楚什么是有效的
not working because there's such a broad
不工作， 因为有这么广泛的
gap Bateen between the way you think
差距 Bateen 你想 的方式
things will work in your mind or even on
事情会在你的脑海中起作用甚至在你的脑海里
paper and the way they work once you sit
纸和他们坐下后的工作方式
and live in the software like actually
并且 像实际一样 住在软件中
spend time living and breathing us out
花时间生活和呼吸我们 出去
we're so different
我们是如此不同
so my philosophy is get to a prototype
所以我的理念是获得 原型
and then what you're really optimizing
然后你真正优化了什么
for speed of iteration like how you can
对于迭代速度，你可以如何
turn the crank how quickly can we
转动曲柄我们能多快
iterate that's the absolutely critical
迭代这绝对是至关重要的
metric of any software project and I had
我所拥有的任何软件项目的指标
a tweet recently that people liked and I
最近人们喜欢和我的推文
totally this is so fundamental to what I
这完全是 我的基础
do is like if you want to measure the
就像你想要衡量的那样
core competency of any software tech
任何软件技术的核心竞争力
company it's the speed at which somebody
公司这是某人的速度
can say hey we really need this word in
可以 说，嘿 ，我们 真的需要这个单词
the product change this word right
产品改变了这个词吧
because it will be more clear to the
因为它会更 清楚
users like what like instead of respond
用户喜欢而不是回应
it's a reply or something but there's
这是回复或其他什么，但有
some from the conception of that idea to
一些从这个想法的概念到
how quickly that single word can be
如何快，一个字可以
changing your software rolled out to
改变你的 软件推出
users that is your lifecycle that's your
用户就是你的 生命周期
health your your heartbeat if your
如果你的健康， 你的心跳健康
heartbeat is like super slow you're
心跳就像超级慢
basically dead no seriously like if it
基本死了没有认真的喜欢它
takes two weeks or even a month to get
需要两个 星期甚至一个月 拿到
that single word change that was oh my
那个单词改变了哦，我的
god this great idea that word is so much
上帝这个伟大的想法，这个词是 如此之多
clearer I'm talking like a super like
更清楚我说话就像一个超级喜欢
everybody's on board for this change
每个人都参与这一变革
it's not like let's just change at work
这不仅仅是让我们 改变工作
cuz we're bored it's like this is an
因为我们很无聊，就像这是一个
awesome change and then it takes a you
令人敬畏的变化 ，然后它需要 你
know months to roll out it's like what
知道几个月推出它就 像是什么
you're dead like you can't iterate you
你死了就像你不能迭代 你
can't do anything right like so anyway
无论如何都不能做任何事情
about the heartbeat it's like get the
关于心跳它就像得到了
the prototype and then iterate on it
原型， 然后重复 上
that's that's what I view is like the
这就是我所 看到的就像是
central tenets of some modern software
一些 现代软件的核心原则
development that's fascinating you put
让你着迷的发展
it that way it's actually so I work in I
就这样，它实际上是我 在我 工作
build a Thomas vehicles and when you
建立一个托马斯车辆，当你
look at what maybe compare Tesla to most
看看特斯拉与大多数人的 比较
other automakers the the psych the
其他汽车制造商的精 极度紧张 的
whatever the heartbeat for Tesla is
不管特斯拉 的心跳 是什么
literally days now in terms of they can
现在从字面上天 他们 而言 能
over-the-air deploy software updates to
无线 部署软件更新到
all their vehicles which is markedly
他们所有的车辆都很明显
different than every other automaker
与其他汽车制造商不同
which takes years to update a piece of
这需要几年时间来更新一块
software and so and that's reflected in
软件等等，这反映在
everything that's the the final product
一切都是最终产品
that's reflected and really how slowly
那反映出来，真的有多缓慢
they adapt to the times
他们适应时代
clear I'm not saying being a hummingbird
清楚我不是说是一只蜂鸟
is the goal either it's like you don't a
是目标，要么就像你 不是
heartbeat it's like so fast it's like
心跳 就像这么快就像
you're your wing you know you're just
你是 你的 翼， 你知道你就是这样
freaking out but like it is a measure of
吓坏了 但是 喜欢它是衡量标准的
health you should have a healthy
健康 你应该 健康
heartbeat it's up to four people
心跳最多四个人
listening this decide what that means
听这个决定了什么意思
but it has to be healthy has to be
但它必须是健康的
reasonable because otherwise you just
合理，因为否则你只是
get me frustrated because like that's
让我感到沮丧， 因为那样的
how you build software you make mistakes
你如何构建软件，你犯了错误
you roll it out you live with it
你把它推出来就可以了
you see what it feels like and say oh
你看到它的感觉并说出来哦
god that was a terrible idea oh my gosh
上帝，这是一个可怕的想法哦，我的天哪
this could be even better if we did why
如果我们这样做，这可能 会更好
right you turn the crank and then the
你转动曲柄 然后转动曲柄
more you do that the faster you get
你做的越多，得到的速度就越快
ahead of your competitors ultimately
最终领先于竞争对手
because you're it's rate of change right
因为你的 变化 率是 正确的
delta-v right how fast are you moving
delta-v 你有多快移动
well within a year you're gonna be miles
一年之内，你 将成为里程
away
远
by the time they catch up with you right
当他们赶上你的时候
like that's the way it works and plus
像这就是它的工作方式，并 加
users like I as a software developer I
用户喜欢 我作为软件 开发人员
love software that's constantly changing
喜欢不断变化的软件
because I don't understand people get
因为我不明白的人 得到
super pissed off when like oh they
当他们喜欢的时候超级生气
changed the software on me how dare they
改变了我的软件他们怎么敢
I'm like yes change the software change
我想是改变软件的变化
it all the time man that is that's what
这一直是男人那是 什么
makes this stuff great is that it can be
使这个东西很棒是可以的
changed so rapidly and become something
变化如此迅速 ，成为一种东西
that that is greater than it is now now
即大于现在是 现在
credit there's some changes that suck I
我 认为有一些变化让 我 感到沮丧
admit I've seen it many times but in
承认我已经多次见过但是 在
general it's like that's what makes
一般而言，这就是它的作用
software cool right is that it is so
软件酷的权利是它是如此
malleable like fighting that is like
可塑性像战斗一样
weird to me because it's like well
对我来说很奇怪，因为它很好
you're fighting the essence of the thing
你正在与事物的本质作斗争
that you're building like that doesn't
你正在构建这样 的不
make sense you want to really embrace
理解你想真正 拥抱
that not not to be a hummingbird but
这不是一个蜂鸟而是
like embrace it to a healthy cycle of
喜欢把它带到一个健康的循环中
your heartbeat right so you talk about
你的心跳正确，所以你 谈谈
that people really don't change it's
人们真的不会改变它
true
真正
that's why probably a lot of the stuff
这就是为什么可能很多 东西
you write about in your blog probably
你 可能 在 博客上 写的
will remain true there's a flip side of
将保持真实有另一 面
the coin people don't change so
硬币人不会改变
investing and understanding people is is
投资和理解人 是
like learning Unix in 1970 because and
喜欢在1970年学习Unix因为和
nothing has changed right like yeah all
一切都没有改变右象在说 所有
those things you've learned about people
你从中学到的关于人的事情
will still be valid 30 40 years from now
从 现在起 40年后 仍然 有效
whereas if you learn the latest
而如果你了解最新的
JavaScript framework that's gonna be
JavaScript框架将会是
good for like two years
好像 两年
right yeah exactly so but if you look at
右耶 正是 如此，但如果你看一下
the future of programming so there's a
编程的未来所以有一个
people component but there's also the
人们组成部分， 但也有
technology itself do you what do you see
技术本身就是你所 看到的
as the future of programming will it
作为编程的未来将是它
change significantly or as as far as you
变化显着或尽可能地变化
can tell people are ultimately
可以告诉人们 最终
programming and so it will not it's not
编程，所以它不会
something that you foresee changing and
你预见到的变化和事物
you fund the month away well you gotta
你得到了很好的资金
go look
去看看
on sort of the basics of programming and
关于编程 和 编程的基础知识
one things that always shocked me is
一件令我震惊的事情是
like source control like I didn't learn
像源代码控制一样，我没有学习
anything about source control I graduate
关于源代码控制的一切我毕业了
from college in 1992 but I remember
1992年从大学毕业， 但我记得
hearing from people like in ladies like
像女士们这样的人听到的
1998-99 like even maybe today they're
1998-99 就像今天他们一样
not learning source control and to me
不学习源代码控制和我
it's like well how can you not learn
它就像你怎么不学习
source control that is so fundamental to
源控制是如此 根本
working with other programmers working
与其他程序员一起工作
in a way they don't lose your work like
在某种程度上，他们 不会失去你的工作
just just basics off the bed literal
只是床上文字的基础知识
bedrock software development is source
基岩软件开发是源头
control now you compare today like
控制你现在比较像今天
github right like Microsoft brought
github 就像微软带来的那样
github which I think was incredibly
github， 我认为是令人难以置信的
smart acquisition move on their part now
聪明的收购 现在 移动他们
they have anybody who wants like
他们有任何想要的人
reasonable source control to go sign
合理的源头控制 去标志
them and github it's all set up for you
他们和github一切都为你而设
right there's tons of walkthroughs tons
就这里有大量的演练吨
of tutorials so from the concept of like
从 类似 的概念 的 教程
has programming advanced from say 1999
编程从1999年开始提前
it's like well hell we have github I
好像地狱我们有github我
mean my god yes right like it's it's
意思是我的上帝是对的，就像它的一样
massively advanced over over what it was
大大超过它的本质
now as to whether program is is
现在是否是程序
significantly different I'm gonna say no
显着不同我会说不
but I think the baseline of like what we
但我认为基线 就像我们一样
view is like fundamentals will continue
观点就像基本面 会继续下去
to go up and actually get better like
上升，实际上变得更好
source control that's one of them in
源代码控制这其中的一个
fundamentals that has gotten I mean
我的意思是基本面
hundreds of orders of magnitude better
数百数量级的更好
than it was 10 20 years ago so those are
而不是 20 年前的 10 年， 所以那些
the fundamentals let me introduce two
基本面让我介绍两个
things that maybe you can comment on so
也许你可以评论的事情
one is mobile phones so that could
一个是手机， 所以可以
fundamentally transform what what
从根本上改变了什么
programming is or maybe not maybe you
编程是或许不是你
can comment on that and the other one is
在可以发表评论 ，另外 一个是
artificial intelligence which promises
承诺的 人工智能
to in some ways to do some of the
在某些方面 做一些
programming for you is one way to think
为您编程 是一种 思考方式
about it so it's really what a
关于它所以它真的是一个
programmer is is using the intelligence
程序员正在使用智能
that's inside your skull to do something
在你的头骨内做某事
useful the hope with artificial
有用的希望 与人工
intelligence is that it does some of the
情报就是 它做了一些
useful parts for you you don't have to
对你有用的部分 ，你不必
think about it so do you see smart
想一想，你看到聪明吗？
phones the fact that everybody has one
打电话说每个人都有一个
and they're getting more and more
而且他们越来越多了
powerful as potentially changing
强大的潜在变化
programming and do you see AI is
编程，你看到AI是
potentially changing problem okay so
可能会改变问题好吧
that's good so smart phones have
这很好，所以智能手机 有
definitely changed I mean since you know
因为你知道， 我的 意思是 肯定的
I guess 2010 that's when they really
我猜2010年就是他们 真的
started getting super popular I mean in
开始越来越受欢迎我的意思是
the last eight years the world has
世界过去八年
literally changed
字面上改变了
like everybody carries a computer around
就像每个人都携带有电脑 周围 的
and that's normal I mean that is such a
这是正常的我的意思 是这样的
huge change in society I think we're
社会的巨大变化 我认为我们是
still dealing with a lot of the positive
先斩后奏了很多 积极 的
negative ramifications of that right
这种权利的负面影响
like everybody's connected all the time
像所有人一直在联系
everybody's on the computer all the time
每个人都在计算机上所有的时间
that was my dream world as a geek right
这是我作为极客的梦想世界
but it's like be careful what you ask
但是要小心你的要求
for right like wow no everybody's a
为了正确，就像 哇，没有人都是
computer it's not quite the utopia that
电脑不是那个 乌托邦
we thought it would be right computers
我们认为这是正确的电脑
can be used for a lot of stuff that's
可以用于 很多 的 东西，这
not necessarily great so to me that's
对我来说 不一定很好
the central focus of the smartphone is
智能手机 的核心焦点 是
just that it puts a computer in front of
只是它把电脑放在 前面
everyone
大家
granted a small touchscreen smallish
授予一个小的触摸屏短小
touchscreen computer but as for
触摸屏计算机，但作为
programming like I don't know I don't
编程就像我不知道我没有
think that I've kind of over time come
我 想 我会随着时间的推移而来
to subscribe to the UNIX view of the
订阅的UNIX视图
world when it comes to programming it's
编程 时的世界
like you want to teach these basic
就像你想教这些基本的
command line things and that is just
命令行的事情就是这样
what programmers gonna be for I think a
什么程序员会为 我认为 一个
long long time I don't think there's any
很长一段时间我不认为有任何
magical like visual programming that's
像视觉编程一样神奇
gonna happen I just I don't know I've
会发生我只是我不知道我
over time I've become a believer in that
随着时间的推移，我已成为相信者
UNIX philosophy it was just you know
UNIX哲学只是你知道的
they kind of had it right with UNIX
他们 有点使用UNIX
that's gonna be the way it hits for a
这将是它击中的方式
long long time and well we'll continue
很长一段时间，我们会继续
to like I said raise the baseline the
像我说的那样提高基线了
tools will get better it'll get simpler
工具会变得更好，它会变得更简单
but it's still fun mental gonna be
但它仍然是有趣的精神
command-line tools you know makes fancy
你知道的命令行工具很有趣
IDs that's kind of it for the
ID 的有点它 的
foreseeable future I'm not seeing any
可预见的未来我没有看到任何
visual programming stuff on the horizon
视觉编程的东西在地平线上
because you can I think like what do you
因为你能 像 我 一样思考你
do on a smartphone that will be directly
在直接的智能手机上做
analogous to programming like I'm trying
类似于我正在尝试的编程
to think right like and there's really
思考 正确，而且确实如此
not much so not necessarily analogous to
不一样， 不一定类似于
programming but the kind of things that
编程，但样的事情
the kind of programs you would need to
你 需要的那种程序
write might need to be very different
写作可能需要非常不同
yeah and the kind of language is I mean
是的， 我的意思是那种语言
but I probably also subscribed to the
但我可能也 订阅了
same just because everything in this
同样只是因为这一切
world might be written in JavaScript
世界可能 用JavaScript编写
oh yeah that's different that's already
哦，是的， 那已经不同了
happening I mean this course is a bit on
发生我的意思是这个课程有点过
discourses itself javascript is another
话语本身javascript是另一个
bet on that side of the table and I
打赌桌子的那边和我
still strongly believe in that so I
仍然坚信这一点，所以我
would say smartphones have mostly a
会说智能手机主要是一个
cultural shift more than a programming
文化转变不仅仅是一种编程
shift now your other question was about
现在转移你的另一个问题是关于
artificial intelligence and like sort of
人工智能和类似 的
devices predicting what you're gonna do
设备预测你要做什么
and I do think there's some strengths to
我 认为有一些 优势
that I think artificial intelligence
我认为人工智能
kind of overselling it in terms of what
在什么方面超越它
it's doing it's more like people are
它正在做的更像是人
predictable right
可预测的权利
people do the same things like let me
人们做 同样的事情就像让我一样
give you an example one one cheque we
举一个例子一一 检查我们
put in a discourse that's in a lot of
放在一个话语这是一个很大 的
big commercial websites is say you log
大商业网站就是说你登录
in from New York City now and then an
从纽约市 不时 出现
hour later you log in from San Francisco
一小时后，您从旧金山登录
like well hmm that's interesting how did
井状嗯， 有趣 如何做
you get from New York to San Francisco
你从纽约 到旧金山
in one hour so at that point you're like
在一个小时内， 所以 那时你就像
okay this is a suspicious login at that
好吧，这是一个可疑的登录
point so we would alert you it's like
这点我们会提醒你它就像
okay but that's an AI right that's just
好吧，但这是一个正确的人工智能
a heuristic of like how did you in one
像你是如何 在一个 启发式 的
hour get 2,000 miles right that doesn't
小时到达 2000英里， 没有
when you grab maybe you're on a VPN
当你抓住可能你 在VPN上
there's other races happen but that's
还有其他种族，但那就是
just a basic prediction based on the
只是一个基于的基本预测
idea that people pretty much don't move
人们几乎 不动的想法
around that much like they may travel
围绕很像 ，他们可能旅行
occasionally but like nobody I mean
偶尔但我不喜欢任何人
unless you're a traveling salesman
除非你是旅行推销员
that's literally we're traveling the
从字面上看，我们正在旅行
world every day like there's so much
每天都有 这样的 世界
repetition and predictability in terms
重复和可预见性 方面
of things you're going to do and I think
我 想你会做的事情
good software anticipate your needs like
良好的软件满足您的需求像
for example Google I think it's called
例如Google 我 认为它 被称为
Google now or whatever that Google thing
谷歌现在或 任何 谷歌的 东西
is that predicts your commute and
是预测你的通勤和
predicts them based on your phone
根据您的手机预测它们
location like where are you every day
位置就像你每天在哪里
well that's probably where you work that
那可能就是你工作的地方
kind of stuff I do think computers can
我认为计算机可以做的事情
get a lot better at that but I hesitate
在 这方面做得更好但我犹豫了
to call it like full-blown AI it's just
调用它像盛放的AI，它只是
computers getting better at like first
电脑越来越好了
of all they have a ton of because every
所有他们都有很多 ，因为每一个
has a smartphone now I'm suddenly how
现在 有一部智能手机 我突然怎么样了
all this data that we didn't have before
以前 我们没有的 所有这些数据
about location about like you know
关于你所知道的位置
communication and feeding that into some
沟通和喂养到一些
some basic heuristics and maybe some
一些基本的启发式， 也许还有一些
fancy algorithms that turn it into
花哨的算法把它变成了
predictions of anticipating your needs
预测您的需求
like like a friend would write like oh
喜欢像朋友一样写哦
hey I I see your home would you like
嘿，我想看你的家吗？
some dinner right like let's go get some
一些晚餐就像让我们去吃点东西吧
food because that's usually what we do
食物，因为这 通常是我们所做的
this time of day right and the context
这一天的正确 时间 和背景
of actually the act of programming DCI
实际上是编程DCI的行为
des improving and making the life of
改善和改善 生活
programming is better I do think that is
编程更好我认为是
possible cuz things a lot of repetition
可能的Cuz的事情 大量 的 重复
in programming right oh you know Clippy
在编程中哦，你知道 Clippy
would be the bad example of oh I see it
将是我看到的坏榜样哦
looks like you're writing a for loop
看起来像 你 的for 循环 写
um but there are patterns in code right
嗯，但代码中有模式
like in and actually libraries are kind
喜欢，实际上图书馆是善良的
of like that right like rather than go
像那样的权利 ，而 不是 去
you know code up your own HTTP request
你知道编写自己的HTTP请求
library it's like what you'd use one of
图书馆就像你使用的一样
the existing ones that we have that's
我们现有的那些
already troubleshot right it's not a I
已经 麻烦了， 这不是我
per se it's just you know building
本身只是你知道建筑
better Lego bricks bigger Lego bricks
更好的乐高积木更大的乐高积木
that have more functionality in them so
在他们 有更多的 功能 ，所以
people don't have to worry about the
人们不必 担心
low-level stuff as much anymore
低水平的东西已经不复存在了
like WordPress for example to me is like
像WordPress一样对我来说 就像
a tool for someone who is in a
适合某人的工具
programmer to do something I mean you
程序员做某事我的意思是你
can turn WordPress into anything it's
可以把WordPress变成任何东西
kind of crazy actually through perla
实际上通过 perla 有点疯狂
plugins right and that's not programming
插件正确，这不是编程
per se it's just Lego bricks stacking
本身它只是乐高积木堆叠
WordPress elements right a little bit of
WordPress的元素右 一 点点
configuration glue so I would say maybe
配置胶水，所以我想说也许吧
in a broader sense what I'm seeing like
从更广泛的意义上说，我看到的是什么
they'll be more gluing and less like
他们会更 粘 ，更不喜欢
actual programming and that's a good
实际编程，这是一个很好的
thing right because most of the stuff
事情是正确的， 因为大部分的东西
you need is kind of out there already
你需要的就是那种了
you said 1970 is Unix do you see PHP and
你说1970年是Unix你看到PHP和
these kind of old remnants of the early
这些早期 的旧遗迹
birth of programming remaining with us
节目的诞生留在我们身边
for a long time like you said Unix in
很长一段时间像你说的Unix 在
itself
本身
do you see ultimately you know this
你看到最终你知道这一点吗？
stuff just being there out of momentum I
只是出于 势头的东西我
kind of do I mean I was a big believer
我是说我是一个大 信徒
in Windows early on and I was a big you
在Windows早期，我是一个伟大的你
know I was like a UNIX what a waste of
知道我就像一个UNIX 什么是浪费
time but over time I've completely
时间，但随着时间的推移，我完全
flipped on that where I was like okay
翻开那个我还好的地方
the UNIX guys were right and pretty much
UNIX人员是对的，差不多
Microsoft and windows were kind of wrong
微软和Windows有点不对劲
at least on the server side not on the
至少在服务器端不上
desktop right you need a GUI you know
桌面权利你需要一个你知道的GUI
what stuff and yeah the two philosophies
什么东西，是的两个哲学
like Apple built on UNIX effectively
就像Apple在UNIX上有效构建的那样
Darwin and on the desktop is a slightly
达尔文和 桌面 上的 是一个轻微的
restore even on the server side where
甚至在服务器端恢复
you're going to be programming now it's
你现在要编程了
question where the program is gonna be
问题该计划将 在 哪里
there's gonna be a lot more like
会有更多的喜欢
client-side programming because
客户端编程因为
technically discourse is client-side
技术上的话语是客户端的
programming the way you get discourse we
编程你得到话语的方式我们
deliver a big ball of JavaScript which
提供JavaScript的一个大球，其
is then execute locally so we're really
然后在本地执行， 所以 我们真的
using a lot more local computing power
使用更多的 本地计算能力
will still retrieve the data obviously
仍会显然检索数据
we have to display the posts on the
我们要在上面显示帖子
screen and so forth but in terms of like
屏幕等等， 但就 类似而言
sorting and a lot of the basic stuff
排序和很多基本的东西
we're using the host processor but to
我们正在使用主机处理器 但是
the extent that a lot of programming is
很多 编程的程度
still gonna be server-side I would say
我会说，仍然是服务器端
yeah the UNIX philosophy definitely one
是的UNIX哲学肯定是一个
and they'll be different veneers over
他们将是不同的贴面
the UNIX but it's still if you if you
UNIX，但如果你，它仍然是你的
peel away one or two layers it's gonna
剥掉一层或两层
be UNIX safe for a long I think UNIX one
我 认为是UNIX 安全 的 UNIX
I mean so definitively it's interesting
我的意思是如此肯定它很有趣
to hear you say that because you've done
听你说，因为你已经完成了
so much excellent work on the Microsoft
关于微软的这么多出色的工作
and aside in terms of back-end
而在后端方面
development cool so what's the future
发展很酷所以未来是什么
hold for Jeff Atwood amid the discourse
在话语中坚持杰夫阿特伍德
continuing the discourse in trying to
继续尝试的话语
improve conversation on the web
改善网络对话
this force is whatever be it is a and
这股力量 无论是什么样的和
originally I call it a five-year project
最初我把它称为一个 为期五年的项目
then really quickly revised that to a
然后真的很快修改 为
ten-year project so where we started in
十年的项目， 所以我们开始
early to that 2013 that's we launched
年初至 2013 这就是 我们推出
the first version so we're still you
第一个版本所以我们仍然是你
know five years in this is the part
知道五年 就是这个部分
where it starts getting good like we
它开始 变得 像我们一样 好
have a good product out this course
这个课程有一个很好的产品
there's any any project building
有任何项目建设
software it takes three years to build
建立软件需要 三年时间
what you wanted to build anyway like v1
你想要建立什么，如v1
is gonna be terrible which it was but
它会变得很糟糕但是
you ship it anyway cuz that's how you
无论如何 你运送 它， 因为 你是这样的
get better at stuff it's about turning
变得更好 的 关于转动的 东西
the crank it's not about v1 being
曲柄不是关于v1的
perfect because that's ridiculous it's
完美， 因为这是荒谬的
about v1 then let's get really good at V
关于v1那么让我们真的很擅长V.
1.1 1.2 1.3 like how fast can we iterate
1.1 1.2 1.3喜欢迭代的速度有多快
and I think we're iterating like crazy
而且我认为我们正在疯狂地迭代
on discourse the point that like it's a
在话语中， 喜欢它的点
really good product now we have serious
真的很好的 产品现在我们认真
momentum and my original vision was I
动力和我 最初的愿景 是我
want to be the wordpress of discussion
想成为 讨论 的 词汇
meaning someone came to you and said I
意思是有人来找 你说 我
want to start a blog although the very
想 开了博客虽然很
question is kind of archaic now it's
问题现在有点过时了
like who actually blogs anymore but I
比如谁真的博客了，但我
wanted the answer to that to be it would
就想这个问题的答案是 它会
be what did WordPress normally because
通常是WordPress因为
that's the obvious choice for blogging
这是博客的明显选择
most the time but if someone said hey I
大部分时间， 但如果有人说 嘿我
want to I need a group of people to get
我希望我需要 一群 人来 获得
together and do something the answer
一起做 一些答案
should be discourse right that should be
应该是话语权利
the default answer for people cuz it's
人们的默认答案就是 这样
open source it's free doesn't cost you
开源它是免费的，不 花你
anything you control you can run it your
任何你控制，你可以运行你的
minimum server across four discourses
四个话语中的最小服务器
five bucks a month at this point they
他们这个月每月五块钱
actually got the VPS prices down it used
实际上 它使用了VPS价格
to be ten dollars a month for one
在 一个月为一个 十块钱
gigabyte of RAM which we where our
我们 所在的千兆字节的RAM
dependent we have a kind of heavy stack
依赖我们有一种沉重的堆栈
like there's a lot of stuff in discourse
就像在话语中有很多东西
you need post grass you need Redis you
你需要 贴 草，你需要Redis你
need Ruby on Rails you need a sidekick
需要Ruby on Rails， 你需要一个伙伴
for scheduling it's not a trivial amount
安排它不是一个微不足道的数额
of stuff because we were architected for
因为我们的架构是为了
like look we're building for the next
喜欢看我们正在构建下一个
ten years I don't care about shared PHP
十年我不 关心共享PHP
hosting that's that's not my model my
托管那不是我的模特我的
idea is like hey you know eventually
想法就像你最终知道的那样
this is gonna be very cheap for
这将是非常 便宜 的
everybody and I want to build it right
我和每个人都希望把它 做好
using again you know hire bigger
再次使用你知道雇用更大
building block levels right that have
正确的积木水平
more requires and there's a wordpress
更多要求，并有一个wordpress
model of wordpress.org juarez calm is
wordpress.org juarez平静的模型是
their central hosting for this course or
他们是这个课程的中心主持人
no there is we're not strictly
不，我们不严格
segmenting into the open source versus
分为开源与
the commercial side we have a hosting
商业方面我们有托管
business that's how this course makes
业务就是 这门课程的制作方式
money is we host discourse instances and
钱是我们主持话语实例和
we have really close relationship with
我们有非常密切的 关系
our customers of the symbiosis of them
我们与他们共生的客户
giving us feedback on the product we
向我们提供有关我们产品的 反馈
definitely wait feedback from customers
绝对等待客户的反馈
a lot heavier than feedback
比反馈重得多
from somebody who just wanders by and
来自一个只是徘徊的人
gives feedback but that's where we make
提供反馈， 但这就是我们所做的
all our money but we don't have a strict
我们所有的 钱，但我们并没有 一个严格的
division we encourage people to use this
我们鼓励 人们使用它
course like the whole point is that it's
当然，总的来说就是它
free right you're anybody can set it up
自由的权利 你是任何人都可以将它设置
I don't want to be the only person that
我 不想成为唯一的人 是
hosts discourse that's absolutely not
主持话语，绝对 不是
the goal but it is a primary way for us
目标，但 它是我们的主要方式
to build a business and it's actually
建立一个企业 ，实际上
kind of a great business I mean the
我的 意思 是一种伟大的 生意
business is going really really well in
生意真的很顺利
terms of hosting so I I used to work at
托管的 条款， 所以我曾经工作过
Google research is a company that's
谷歌研究 是一家公司
basically funded on advertisement so
基本上 是广告 资助的
it's Facebook let me ask if you can
这是Facebook 让我问你是否可以
comment on it
评论它
I think advertisement is best so you'd
我认为广告是最好的， 所以你
be extremely critical on what ads are
对广告是什么非常关键
but at its best it's actually serving
但最好它实际上是服务
you in a sense as giving you it's
从某种意义上说， 就像给你它一样
connecting you to what you would want to
将你连接到你想要的 东西
explore so it's like related posts or
探索所以它就像相关的帖子或
related content is the same that's the
相关的内容是相同的是这样的
best of advertisement so this course is
最好的广告所以这个课程是
connecting people based on their
基于连接的 人
interests it seems like a place where
兴趣似乎是一个地方
advertisement at its best could actually
最好的广告实际上 可以
serve the users is that something that
为用户服务就是那样的东西
you're considering thinking about as a
你正在考虑考虑作为一个
way to bring to financially support the
方法，使从财政上支持
platform that's interesting because I
这个平台很有意思，因为我
actually have a contrarian view of
实际上有逆向观点
advertising which I kind of agree with
广告，我有一种认同
you I recently installed that blocker
你我最近安装了那个拦截器
like reluctantly because I don't like to
喜欢不情愿，因为我不喜欢
do that but like the performance of the
这样做， 但喜欢的表现
ads man like they're so heavy now and
广告男人现在和他们一样沉重
like it's just crazy so like it's almost
喜欢它只是疯了所以喜欢它几乎
like a performance argument more than
比起表演论证更多
like I actually am Pro ads and I
就像我实际上是专业广告 和我
contrary I have a contrarian viewpoint I
相反， 我有逆向观点
agree with you if you do ads right it's
如果你正确做广告，请同意你的意见
showing you stuff you'll be interested
向你展示你会 感兴趣的东西
in anyway like I don't mind that that
无论如何，我不介意那样
actually is kind of a good thing
实际上 是种 好 东西
so plus I think it's it's rational to
所以加上我认为这是理性的
want to support the people that are
要支持 那些 人
doing this work through seeing their ads
通过查看广告来完成这项工作
and but that said I run adblock now
但是那说我现在运行adblock
which I I didn't want to do but I was
哪个II不想做，但我是
convinced by all these artists like 30
被所有这​​些艺术家所信服，如30
40 megabytes of stuff just to serve you
40兆的东西 只是 为你服务
ads yeah it feels like as now or like
广告是的感觉就像现在或像
the experts exchange of whenever you
专家交流你 什么时候
started Stack Overflow it's a little bit
启动Stack Overflow 它有点
it's all there's so many companies and
这就是有这么多公司和
Antec though it's embarrassing like you
Antec虽然像你一样令人尴尬
can do that if you see those logo charts
如果 你看到那些徽标图表 就可以做到这一点
of like just a whole page just like you
就像 你一样整整一页
can't even see them they're so small
甚至看不到他们 这么小
there's so many companies in the space
这个领域有这么多公司
but since you brought it up I do want to
但是既然你提出来了我就是这么想的
point out that very very few discourse
指出非常少的话语
sites
网站
run using an ad-supported model it's not
使用广告支持的模型运行它不是
effective like it's too diluted it's too
有效的， 就像它太稀释了一样
weird it doesn't pay well and like users
奇怪的是它并不能很好地支付用户
hate it so it's a combination of like
恨它， 所以它是喜欢的组合
users hate it it doesn't actually work
用户讨厌它， 它 实际上 并没有 正常工作
that well in practice like in theory yes
这在实践中很好， 就像在理论上一样
I agree with you but if you clean fast
我同意你的意见， 但如果 你快速清洁的话
ads that were exactly the stuff you
广告，这正是 你 的 东西
would be interested awesome we're so far
我们感兴趣的是我们到目前为止
from that though right like Google does
从正确的，虽然 像谷歌做
an okay job
一份好的工作
retargeting and stuff like that but in
重新定位和类似的东西，但在
the in in the real world
在现实世界中
discourse sites rarely can make ads work
话语网站很少能让广告发挥作用
it just doesn't work for so many reasons
它只是因为这么多原因而无效
but you know it does work is
但你知道它确实有效
subscriptions patreon affiliate codes
订阅patreon会员代码
for like Amazon of like just oh here
像亚马逊一样喜欢哦
here's a cool yo-yo click and then you
这是一个很酷的溜溜球 点击然后你
click and go to Amazon they get a small
点击并转到亚马逊他们得到一个小
percentage of that which is fair I think
我 认为 这是公平的百分比
because you saw the yo-yo on that site
因为你 在那个网站上 看过 溜溜球
and you click through and you bought it
然后你点击进去就买了它
right that's fair for them to get 5% of
对他们来说 ，得到5％ 的公平是 正确 的
that or 2% of that or whatever it is
的 该 人或2％ 或不管它 是 什么
those things definitely work in fact a
事实上这些东西肯定是有效的
site that I used to participate on a lot
网站，我用 了很多 参与
I helped the owner one things I I got
我帮助了主人一件事
them switched to discourse obviously
他们明显转向话语
paid them to switch to discourse because
支付他们切换到 话语， 因为
I was like look you guys got a switch I
我觉得你们有一个开关我
can't come here anymore all this
所有 这 一切都不能再来这里了
terrible in software but I was like a
软件很 可怕 ，但我就像一个
look and on top of that like you're
外观和最重要的是 像你
serving people ads that they hate like
为人们提供他们讨厌的广告
you should just go full on patreon
你应该充分利用patreon
because he had a little bit of patreon
因为他有一点点 patreon
go full on patreon do the Amazon
在亚马逊上完成patreon
affiliates thing for any Amazon links to
任何亚马逊链接的附属机构
get posted and just do that and just
得到发布，只是这样做
triple down on that stuff and that's
三倍下来 的 东西，这就是
worked really well for them and this
为他们 和这个工作非常好
creator in particular so that stuff
特别是创造者那样的东西
works but traditional ads I mean
我的意思是传统广告有效
definitely not working at least on this
绝对不会至少在这方面工作
course so last question you've created
当然，你创造的最后一个问题
the code keyboard I've programmed most
我编程最多的代码键盘
of my adult life and a Kinesis keyboard
我的成年生活和Kinesis键盘
I have one upstairs now can you describe
我 现在 在楼上有一个 你可以描述一下吗？
what a mechanical keyboard is and why is
机械键盘是 什么 ，为什么
it something that makes you happy well
它让 你快乐
you know this is another fetish item
你知道这是另一种恋物癖
really like it's not required you can do
真的很喜欢 你 不需要 你能做到的
programming on any kind of keyboard
在任何类型 的 键盘 上编程
right even like an on-screen keyboard oh
就像一个屏幕键盘哦
god that's terrifying
上帝，这是可怕的
right like well you could but if you
右像 以及你可以 ， 但 如果你
look back to the early days computing
回望 初期 计算
there were chiclet keyboards which are I
我有一个chiclet键盘
think those are awful right but what's a
认为那些是可怕的，但是什么 是
chick like you were oh god okay well
像你这样的小妞哦，上帝还好吧
it's just like thin rubber membranes all
它就像薄橡胶膜 全部
the rubber ones oh no super bad right
橡胶的哦，没有超级坏的权利
yeah so it's a fetish item all it really
是的所以这真是一件迷信物品
says is look I care really about
说 是 我真的很在乎
keyboards because the keyboard is the
键盘是因为键盘是
primary
主
method of communication with computer
与计算机通信的方法
right so it's just like having a nice
右所以它 就像有一个不错的
mic for this this podcast you want a
你想要 这个播客的麦克风
nice keyboard right because it has tat
很好的键盘因为它有tat
very tactile feel I can tell exactly
非常有触觉，我可以准确地说出来
when I press the key I get that little
当我按下键时，我得到了那么一点
click so oh and it feels good and it's
点击这样哦， 感觉很好，就是 这样
also kind of a fetish shot it was like
它也像是一种迷恋镜头
wow I care enough about programming that
哇， 我关心不够 有关编程 的是
I care about the tool the primary tool
我关心工具是主要工具
that I use committing to computer make
我使用计算机制作
sure it's as good as it feels good to
确定它和感觉一样好
use for me and like I can be very
使用我，就像我可以 很
productive with it so to be honest it's
有生产力所以说实话
a little bit of a fetish item but a good
一点点恋物癖但好一点
one it indicates that you're serious and
一， 它表明 你是认真的
in case you're interested it indicates
万一你感兴趣 它表示
that you care about the fundamentals
你关心 基本面
because you know what makes you a good
因为你知道是什么让你变得更好
programmer being able to type really
程序员能够真正打字
fast right like this is true right so a
像这样的 快速 权利是正确的， 所以a
core skill is just being able to type
核心技能只是 能够键入
fast enough to get your ideas out of
足够快，可以让你的想法
your head into the codebase so just
你只是进入代码库
practicing your typing can make you a
练习你的打字可以让你成为一个
better programmer it is also something
更好的程序员它也是一些东西
that makes you well makes you enjoy
这让你很好，让你享受
typing correct the actual act something
键入正确的实际行为
about the process I got played piano
关于我演奏钢琴的过程
it's time so there's a tactile feel that
是的时候有一种触觉的感觉
ultimately feeds the passion makes you
最终激发你的激情
happy right no totally that's it I mean
幸福没有完全就是 我的意思
and it's funny because artisanal
这很有趣 因为 手工艺
keyboards have exploded like mass drop
键盘像质量下降一样爆炸
has gone ballistic with this stuff
用这些东西搞砸了
there's probably like 500 keyboard
可能有500个键盘
projects on mass drop alone and there's
关于质量下降的项目和那里
some other guy I follow on Twitter I
我 在Twitter上关注的其他人
used to write for this the site the tech
过去为这个网站写技术
report way back in the day and he's like
报道当天回来，他就像
every week he's just posting like what I
每个星期他都像我一样张贴
call keyboard porn of like just cool
打电话键盘色情就好酷
keyboards like how my god they look
键盘就像 他们的 神 一样
really cool right like that's like how
非常酷，就像那样
many keyboards this guy yeah
很多键盘这家伙是啊
it's got me with yo-yos how many rows do
它让我跟你溜溜球有多少 行
you have how many do you need well
你有多少需要 好
technically one but I like a lot I don't
技术上一个，但我喜欢 很多 我不喜欢
know why so same thing with keyboards so
知道为什么键盘如此相同
yeah they're awesome
是的， 他们很棒
like I highly recommend anybody who
我强烈推荐任何人
doesn't have a mechanical to research it
没有机械研究它
look into it and see what you like and
看看它， 看看 你喜欢 什么
you know it's ultimately a fetish item
你知道这最终是一件迷信物品
but I think these sort of items these
但我觉得这些物品都是这些
religious artifacts that we have are
我们拥有的宗教文物
part of what make us human like that
是什么让我们成为人类的一部分
that part you important right it's kind
那部分你重要的是它的善良
of makes life worth living and yes it's
让生活变得有价值 ， 是的
not necessary in the strictest sense but
严格意义上不是必要的，但
ain't nothing necessary if you think of
如果你想到的话，并非没有必要
yet right like and so yeah why not so
然而就是这样，所以是的，为什么不这样
sure Jeff thank you so much for talking
杰夫非常感谢你的谈话
today yeah you're welcome thanks for
今天是的， 谢谢 你
having
有
you
您